<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accounts on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Accounts on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Commandline flags accounts add accounts inspect accounts remove accounts ocis-accounts accounts server accounts version accounts list accounts rebuildIndex accounts update       Configuration Configuration using config files Out of the box extensions will attempt to read configuration details from:
/etc/ocis $HOME/.ocis ./config For this configuration to be picked up, have a look at your extension root command and look for which default config name it has assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRPC API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/accounts/grpc/</guid>
      <description>accounts.proto  Account AddMemberRequest CreateAccountRequest CreateGroupRequest DeleteAccountRequest DeleteGroupRequest GetAccountRequest GetGroupRequest Group Identities ListAccountsRequest ListAccountsResponse ListGroupsRequest ListGroupsResponse ListMembersRequest ListMembersResponse OnPremisesProvisioningError PasswordProfile RebuildIndexRequest RebuildIndexResponse RemoveMemberRequest UpdateAccountRequest UpdateGroupRequest AccountsService GroupsService IndexService   Scalar Value Types     accounts.proto Account Account follows the properties of the ms graph api user resuorce. See https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/api/resources/user?view=graph-rest-1.0#properties
   Field Type Label Description     id string  The unique identifier for the user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>