<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Introduce an accounts service</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</guid>
      <description>Status: superseded by ADR-0003 Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm, @micbar, @pmaier1 Date: 2020-06-15 Technical Story: persist accounts
Context and Problem Statement To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email und username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes. While there is an account porting protocol that describes how a relying party (RP) such as ownCloud should behave, it still requires the RP to maintain its own user identifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy as an app in ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/deployments/oc10-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/deployments/oc10-app/</guid>
      <description>Compatibility Introduction Prerequisites Deploying ownCloud Web Configure oauth2 Configure ownCloud 10 Set ownCloud Web address Configure link routing Make ownCloud Web the default web interface Configure ownCloud Web Integrate ownCloud Classic features in ownCloud Web Add links to the app switcher Add links to the user menu ONLYOFFICE Collabora Online Additional configuration for certain core apps Preview app Text-Editor app Accessing ownCloud Web Compatibility Please note that the usage of Web UI and ownCloud 10 as backend is not recommended starting with version 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:03:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Framework Overview of the approach In-depth configuration Flows Examples Expected loading locations Only config files Using ENV variables Workflows Supervised Unsupervised Shared Values Log config keys Default config values (in yaml) Configuration Framework In order to simplify deployments and development the configuration model from oCIS aims to be simple yet flexible.
Overview of the approach In-depth configuration Since we include a set of predefined extensions within the single binary, configuring an extension can be done in a variety of ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Components of the File picker File picker Location picker ownCloud File picker is a web component which can be integrated into existing web applications. It connects to an ownCloud server and enables a user to select resources which are then provided in a response of a fired event. Visit installation to see how to integrate the File picker into your product.
Please be aware that the File picker provides you with an object representation of the resource and not the actual content itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Persist accounts in a CS3 storage</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm Date: 2020-08-21 Technical Story: File system based indexing
Context and Problem Statement To set up High Availability (HA) or a geo-replicated setup we need to persist accounts in a distributed way. To efficiently query the accounts by email or username, and not only by id, they need to be indexed. Unfortunately, the bleve index we currently store locally on disk cannot be shared by multiple instances, preventing a scale out deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Use external User Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0003-external-user-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0003-external-user-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: superseded by 17. Allow read only external User Management Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2022-02-08 Technical Story: Skip account-service by talking to CS3 user-api
Context and Problem Statement To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email and username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</guid>
      <description>Setup authentication OpenID Connect config OAuth2 config Pass bearer token Install File picker package Select browser storage Integrate in HTML page with vanilla JavaScript Integrate in Vue web application Set correct variation Theming Buttons and events Select button Cancel button Setup authentication The config for the server backend and authentication needs to be provided in json format. The full set of options is listed below in two examples. One for authentication with OAuth2 and one with OpenID Connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Support Hot Migration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0004-support-hot-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0004-support-hot-migration/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-03-16 Technical Story: [description | ticket/issue URL]
Context and Problem Statement Migration is one of the most important topics of the oCIS story. We need to provide a concept how to migrate from oC10 to oCIS.
Decision Drivers Do not lose file blob or metadata. To prevent a sync surge from clients the etag for files should be migrated. To prevent internal links from breaking or pointing to wrong files the file id of existing files needs to be migrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Resources</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</guid>
      <description>Access resources Perform actions with selected resources If using File picker as a web component, it is returning selected resources via events called select and update. To access them, you need to set an event listener where you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to get them as part of the response of the callback function.
Access resources &amp;lt;file-picker id=&amp;#34;file-picker&amp;#34; variation=&amp;#34;resource&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/file-picker&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const item = document.getElementById(&amp;#39;file-picker&amp;#39;) let resources = [] item.addEventListener(&amp;#39;select&amp;#39;, event =&amp;gt; { resources = event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS and Containers</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-and-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-and-containers/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Native Why do we recommend to work with containers?
Lightweight Containers are more lightweight than VMs. It is easier to work with shared volumes and networks because they are isolated from the host system. Dependencies The container images have all dependencies installed and the maintainer takes care for keeping them up-to-date. Scaling In addition to that, containers help with scaling. You can run multiple instances of one container and distribute them across hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Account Management through CS3 API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0005-cs3-api-account-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0005-cs3-api-account-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-04-12 Technical Story: Write only management API for User and Group resources
Context and Problem Statement What would be a more effective way of using network resources and handle account management within the oCIS-Reva ecosystem? Separating account management at the service level is pragmatic and allows for fast iterations, but also steadily accumulates inconsistencies and bloats technical debt.
Decision Drivers Reduce number of network calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</guid>
      <description>Variation File Picker Location Picker Actions Select Cancel It is possible to customise certain parts of the File Picker with the help of props.
Variation File picker comes in two different variations - File Picker and Location Picker. To specify which one should be used, set property variation to resource or location.
File Picker File picker variation is used to select resources from within your ownCloud instace. It is possible to select multiple files and folders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Service Discovery within oCIS and Reva</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0006-service-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0006-service-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-04-19 Technical Story: Introduce Named Services.
Context and Problem Statement Reva relies heavily on config files. A known implication of this approach are having to know a-priori where a service is running (host + port). We want to move away from hardcoded values and rely instead on named services for service discovery. Furthermore, we would like both platforms (Reva + oCIS) to have the same source of truth at any given time, not having one to notify the other whenever a service status changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Provider</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spacesprovider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spacesprovider/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this. Spaces Provider A storage provider manages resources identified by a reference by accessing a storage system with a storage driver.
Frontend The oCIS frontend service starts all services that handle incoming HTTP requests:
ocdav for ownCloud flavoured WebDAV ocs for sharing, user provisioning, capabilities and other OCS API endpoints datagateway for up and downloads TODO: ocm WebDAV The ocdav service not only handles all WebDAV requests under (remote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Component reference</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</guid>
      <description>Props Events &amp;lt;file-picker&amp;gt; Props Property Type Default Description variation String Specifies if File Picker (resource) or Location Picker (location) should be used configLocation String window.location.origin + &#39;/file-picker-config.json&#39; Defines where the config file should be located bearerToken String null Bearer token used for requests authentication. If specified, authorization step is skipped configObject `String Object` isSdkProvided Boolean false Asserts whether ownCloud SDK is already initialised in the consuming app selectBtnLabel String null Replaces the select button label isSelectBtnDisplayed Boolean true Asserts whether the select button should be displayed cancelBtnLabel String nulll Displays the cancel button and uses the given value as a label isOdsProvided Boolean false Asserts whether the ownCloud Design System has been already initialised in the consuming app locale String null Sets the language in which the File Picker should be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. Open Graph API for oCIS File Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0007-api-for-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0007-api-for-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-03-19 Technical Story: API to enable the concept of Spaces
Context and Problem Statement As one of the building blocks for Spaces in oCIS we plan to add an API that returns information about available spaces. This ADR discusses the API design oriented on the Microsoft Graph API.
Note: The term &amp;ldquo;spaces&amp;rdquo; is used here in the context of &amp;ldquo;a space where files can be saved&amp;rdquo;, similar to a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</guid>
      <description>Focusing content of File Picker Initial folder load focus File Picker comes only with partial focus management. If you want to focus an element, it needs to be achieved through a code in the consuming app.
Focusing content of File Picker If you&amp;rsquo;re including File Picker as a web component, managing focus is slightly different from focusing content of any other component in the DOM tree. Since web component are living in shadow root, we need to send the focus into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover oCIS with Docker</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-local-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-local-docker/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Start oCIS with docker compose Create the project Initialize Mount the config file Apply the changes Open the port 9200 to the outside Persist data, restart and logging Pin the oCIS version Wrapping up Prerequisites Local docker installation (e.g. Docker for Desktop) Check oCIS and Containers Start oCIS with docker compose Create the project Use the following skeleton as a docker-compose.yml:
mkdir simple-ocis &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ cd simple-ocis &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ touch docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8. Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0008-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0008-configuration/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-05-03 Context and Problem Statement As per urfave/cli&amp;rsquo;s doc:
The precedence for flag value sources is as follows (highest to lowest):
Command line flag value from user Environment variable (if specified) Configuration file (if specified) Default defined on the flag An issue arises in point 2, in the sense that configuration file refers to a single file containing the value for the env variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Data using rclone</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/migrate-data-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/migrate-data-rclone/</guid>
      <description>People keep asking on how to migrate data from other cloud storage to Infinite Scale.
There are too many cloud variants and use cases out there to have a migration path for all at hand, but let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can start with: There is the famous Swiss army knife for clouds called rclone available.
The awesome rclone tool makes it easy to migrate data from one installation to another on a user per user base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9. Extension Template</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0009-extension-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0009-extension-template/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @c0rby Date: 2021-06-10 Technical Story: [description | ticket/issue URL] Context and Problem Statement We want to accelerate and simplify extension development by removing the necessity to type or copy the boilerplate code. Can we provide a template or a similar mechanism to aid when developing new extensions?
Decision Drivers The solution should be easily maintainable. It should always be up-to-date. The solution should be easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Registry</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spacesregistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spacesregistry/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this. Storage Space Registries A storage spaces registry manages the namespace for a user: it is used by clients to look up storage spaces a user has access to, the /dav/spaces endpoint to access it via WabDAV, and where the client should mount it in the users personal namespace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Extension Policies</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0010-policy-enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0010-policy-enforcement/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2021-06-30 Context and Problem Statement There should be a way to impose certain limitations in areas of the code that require licensing. This document researches an approach to achieve this goal, while limiting the scope to the enforcement side of it. The architecture for a policy system must be composed of 2 parts:
License creation and validation Enforcement It is desirable to keep both systems isolated, since the implementation of the latter has to be done within the constraints of the codebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Deployment</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/continuous_deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/continuous_deployment/</guid>
      <description>oCIS with Traefik Latest Daily Released oCIS with WOPI server Latest Daily Released oCIS with latest ownCloud Web Latest Daily oCIS with Keycloak Latest Released oCIS with S3 storage backend (MinIO) Latest oCIS with LDAP for users and groups Latest Released We are continuously deploying the following deployment examples. Every example is deployed in two flavors:
Latest: reflects the current master branch state of oCIS and will be updated with every commit to master Daily: reflects the master branch state of oCIS as of the time of deployment Released: reflects the newest release state (currently latest release of version 1) and will be updated with every release The configuration for the continuous deployment can be found in the oCIS repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring &amp; Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/monitoring-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/monitoring-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Overview about the proposed solution Monitoring &amp;amp; tracing clients Monitoring &amp;amp; tracing server Monitoring and tracing gives developers and admin insights into a complex system, in this case oCIS.
If you are a developer and want to trace during developing you should have a look at example server setup.
This documentation describes how to set up a long-running monitoring &amp;amp; tracing infrastructure for one or multiple oCIS servers or deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-registry/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-registry/apps/</guid>
      <description>oCIS is all about files. But most of the time you want to do something with files that is beyond the basic upload, download and share behavior. Therefore, oCIS has a concept for apps, that can handle specific file types, so-called mime types.
App provider capability The capabilities endpoint (e.g. https://localhost:9200/ocs/v1.php/cloud/capabilities?format=json) gives you following capabilities which are relevant for the app provider:
{ &amp;#34;ocs&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;data&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;capabilities&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;files&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;app_providers&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;enabled&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation Docker Source Code Configuration Options Scripts and Styles Sentry Setting up backend and running Running Installation Docker Make sure to have Docker, Docker-Compose, Node.js and pnpm installed.
This setup currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on Windows out of the box.
Workaround One of our contributors has opened a PR to a dependency that prevents us from successfully bundling the frontend. Feel free to check out [his changes](https://github.com/egoist/rollup-plugin-postcss/pull/384) and build them locally if you absolutely want to work on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resetting a lost administrator password</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/admin_password_reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/admin_password_reset/</guid>
      <description>Resetting a lost administrator password By default, when using oCIS with the builtin IDM an ad generates the user admin (DN uid=admin,ou=users,o=libregraph-idm) if, for any reason, the password of that user is lost, it can be reset using the resetpassword sub-command:
ocis idm resetpassword It will prompt for a new password and set the password of that user accordingly. Note: As this command is accessing the idm database directly will only work while ocis is not running and nothing else is accessing database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. WebUI URL format</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0011-global-url-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0011-global-url-format/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @fschade, @tbsbdr, @kulmann Date: 2021-07-07 Context and Problem Statement When speaking about URLs we have to make a difference between browser URLs and API URLs. Only browser URLs are visible to end users and will be bookmarked. The currently existing and bookmarked ownCloud 10 URLs look something like this:
GET https://demo.owncloud.com/apps/files/?dir=/path/to/resource&amp;amp;fileid=5472225 303 Location: https://demo.owncloud.com/apps/files/?dir=/path/to/resource When the URL contains a fileid parameter the server will look up the corresponding dir, overwriting whatever was set before the redirect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0012-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0012-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @mstingl, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2021-08-17 Context and Problem Statement At the time of this writing we are in a situation where our logs have too much verbosity, rendering impossible or rather difficult to debug an instance. For this reason we are giving some care to our traces by updating dependencies from OpenCensus to OpenTelemetry.
Decision Drivers We don&amp;rsquo;t want to rely only on logs to debug an instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage drivers</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/storagedrivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/storagedrivers/</guid>
      <description>A storage driver implements access to a storage system:
It maps the path and id based CS3 references to an appropriate storage system specific reference, e.g.:
eos file ids posix inodes or paths deconstructed filesystem nodes Storage providers To manage the file tree oCIS uses storage providers that are accessing the underlying storage using a storage driver. The driver can be used to change the implementation of a storage aspect to better reflect the actual underlying storage capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Locking</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0013-locking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0013-locking/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @jojowein, @dragotin, @micbar, @tbsbdr, @wkloucek Date: 2021-11-03 Context and Problem Statement At the time of this writing no locking mechanisms exists in oCIS / REVA for both directories and files. The CS3org WOPI server implements a file based locking in order to lock files. This ADR discusses if this approach is ok for the general availability of oCIS or if changes are needed.
Decision Drivers Is the current situation acceptable for the GA Is locking needed or can we have oCIS / REVA without locking Considered Options File based locking No locking CS3 API locking Decision Outcome For the GA we chose option 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Microservices Runtime</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0014-microservices-runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0014-microservices-runtime/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @mstingl, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2022-01-21 Context and Problem Statement In an environment where shipping a single binary makes it easier for the end user to use oCIS, embedding a whole family of microservices within a package and running it leveraging the use of the Go language has plenty of value. In such environment, a runtime is necessary to orchestrate the services that run within it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. oCIS Event System</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0015-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0015-events/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @c0rby, @wkloucek Date: 2022-01-21 Context and Problem Statement Overview To be able to implement simple, flexible and independent inter service communication there is the idea to implement an event system in oCIS. A service can send out events which are received by one or more other services. The receiving service can cause different kinds of actions based on the event by utilizing the information that the event carries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Repository structure Starting points Developing oCIS Developing extensions Requirements We want contribution to oCIS and the creation of extensions to be as easy as possible. So we are trying to reflect this in the tooling. It should be kept simple and quick to be set up.
Besides standard development tools like git and a text editor, you need the following software for development:
Go &amp;gt;= v1.21 (install instructions) pnpm (install instructions) docker (install instructions) docker-compose (install instructions) If you find tools needed besides the mentioned above, please feel free to open an issue or open a PR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/namespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/namespaces/</guid>
      <description>A namespace is a set of paths with a common prefix. Depending on the endpoint you are talking to you will encounter a different kind of namespace: In ownCloud 10 all paths are considered relative to the users home. The CS3 API uses a global namespace and the storage providers use a local namespace with paths relative to the storage providers root.
The different paths in the namespaces need to be translated while passing references from service to service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. Storage for Files Metadata</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0016-files-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0016-files-metadata/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @dragotin, @micbar, @C0rby Date: 2022-02-04 Context and Problem Statement In addition to the file content we need to store metadata which is attached to a file. Metadata describes additional properties of a file. These properties need to be stored as close as possible to the file content to avoid inconsistencies. Metadata are key to workflows and search. We consider them as an additional value which enhances the file content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemd service</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/systemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/systemd/</guid>
      <description>Install the oCIS binary Systemd service definition Starting the oCIS service Install the oCIS binary Download the oCIS binary of your preferred version and for your CPU architecture and operating system from download.owncloud.com.
Rename the downloaded binary to ocis and move it to /usr/bin/. As a next step, you need to mark it as executable with chmod +x /usr/bin/ocis.
When you now run ocis help on your command line, you should see the available options for the oCIS command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Remote Setup</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/basic-remote-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/basic-remote-setup/</guid>
      <description>Start the oCIS fullstack server from binary Using automatically generated certificates Using already present certificates Start the oCIS fullstack server with Docker Compose The default configuration of the oCIS binary and the owncloud/ocis docker image assume, that you access oCIS on localhost. This enables you to do quick testing and development without any configuration.
If you need to access oCIS running in a docker container, on a VM or a remote machine via another hostname than localhost, you need to configure this hostname in oCIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. Allow read only external User Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0017-allow-read-only-external-user-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0017-allow-read-only-external-user-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @rhafer Date: 2022-02-08 Context and Problem Statement oCIS needs to be integrated with various external Authentication and Identity Management Systems. Usually oCIS will have no administrative access to such a system and we will not be allowed to reconfigure it to suit our needs (e.g. we will not be able to enhance the schema of an already existing LDAP Directory). In most of the cases our access will be read-only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/users/</guid>
      <description>TODO add this to the storage overview? or is this a different part? That should be started as a separate service ? And documented elsewhere, e.g. in the accounts?
User and Group provisioning In oc10 users are identified by a username, which cannot change, because it is used as a foreign key in several tables. For oCIS we are internally identifying users by a UUID, while using the username in the WebDAV and OCS APIs for backwards compatability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminology</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/terminology/</guid>
      <description>Communication is hard. And clear communication is even harder. You may encounter the following terms throughout the documentation, in the code or when talking to other developers. Just keep in mind that whenever you hear or read storage, that term needs to be clarified, because on its own it is too vague. PR welcome.
Logical concepts Resources A resource is the basic building block that oCIS manages. It can be of different types:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. File Search API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0018-file-search-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0018-file-search-api/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby Date: 2022-03-18 Context and Problem Statement The ability to find files based on certain search terms is a key requirement for a system that provides the ability to store unstructured data on a large scale.
Decision Drivers Have a simple yet powerful, scalable and performant way of finding files in oCIS Be able to construct intelligent searches based on metadata Allow the user to filter the search queries based on metadata Considered Options Libre Graph API WebDAV API Decision Outcome Chosen option: WebDAV API because the current WebUI is compatible with that API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Changes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/proposedchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/proposedchanges/</guid>
      <description>Some architectural changes still need to be clarified or changed. Maybe an ADR is in order for all of the below.
Reva Gateway changes A dedicated shares storage provider Currently, when a user accepts a share, a cs3 reference is created in the users /home/shares folder. This reference represents the mount point of a share and can be renamed, similar to the share jail in ownCloud 10. This spreads the metadata of a share in two places:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. File Search Index</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0019-file-search-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0019-file-search-index/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby Date: 2022-03-18 Context and Problem Statement The ability to find files based on certain search terms is a key requirement for a system that provides the ability to store unstructured data on a large scale.
More sophisticated search capabilities are expected and can be implemented, especially based on metadata.
To trigger the indexing of a file, the search service listens to create, update and delete events on the internal event bus of oCIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registry</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/registry/</guid>
      <description>To be able to communicate with each other, services need to register in a common registry.
Configuration The type of registry to use can be configured with the MICRO_REGISTRY environment variable. Supported values are:
memory Setting the environment variable to memory starts an inmemory registry. This only works with the single binary deployment.
nats-js-kv (Default) Set the environment variable to nats-js-kv or leave it empty to use a nats-js key value store as registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LDAP - Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/identity-provider/ldap-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/identity-provider/ldap-active-directory/</guid>
      <description> Overview oCIS can be configured using Active Directory as identity provider.
Configuration Example This configuration is an example for using Samba4 AD as well as a Windows Server 2022 as the LDAP backend for oCIS. It is intended as guideline and first starting point.
OCIS_LDAP_URI=ldaps://xxxxxxxxx OCIS_LDAP_INSECURE=&amp;#34;true&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_BIND_DN=&amp;#34;cn=administrator,cn=users,xxxxxxxxxx&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD=xxxxxxx OCIS_LDAP_DISABLE_USER_MECHANISM=&amp;#34;none&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_GROUP_BASE_DN=&amp;#34;dc=owncloud,dc=test&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_GROUP_OBJECTCLASS=&amp;#34;group&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_GROUP_SCHEMA_ID=&amp;#34;objectGUID&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_GROUP_SCHEMA_ID_IS_OCTETSTRING=&amp;#34;true&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_GROUP_SCHEMA_GROUPNAME=&amp;#34;cn&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_USER_BASE_DN=&amp;#34;dc=owncloud,dc=test&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_USER_OBJECTCLASS=&amp;#34;user&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_USER_SCHEMA_ID=&amp;#34;objectGUID&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_USER_SCHEMA_ID_IS_OCTETSTRING=&amp;#34;true&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_USER_SCHEMA_USERNAME=&amp;#34;sAMAccountName&amp;#34; OCIS_LDAP_LOGIN_ATTRIBUTES=&amp;#34;sAMAccountName&amp;#34; IDP_LDAP_LOGIN_ATTRIBUTE=&amp;#34;sAMAccountName&amp;#34; IDP_LDAP_UUID_ATTRIBUTE=&amp;#34;objectGUID&amp;#34; IDP_LDAP_UUID_ATTRIBUTE_TYPE=binary GRAPH_LDAP_SERVER_WRITE_ENABLED=&amp;#34;false&amp;#34; OCIS_EXCLUDE_RUN_SERVICES=idm OCIS_ADMIN_USER_ID=&amp;#34;&amp;lt;objectGUID-value-of-the-default-admin-user&amp;gt;&amp;#34; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Envvar Naming Scope</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvar-scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvar-scopes/</guid>
      <description>The scope of an environment variable can be derived from its name. Therefore it is important to follow the correct naming scheme to enable easy and proper identification. This is important when either:
a new local envvar is introduced. a new global envvar is added to an existing local envvar. Envvar Definition A variable that is only used in a particular service is a local envvar. A variable that is used in more than one service is a global envvar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Service Checklist</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/new-service-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/new-service-checklist/</guid>
      <description>When a new service gets introduced, this checklist is a good startingpoint for things that need to be completed before the service gets published (merged). This list is without claim of completeness or correct sort order.
New Service Checklist Use this checklist with copy/paste in your PR - right from the beginning. It renders correctly in your PR.
- [ ] Provide a README.md for that service in the root folder of that service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/antivirus/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/antivirus/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 # Autogenerated # Filename: antivirus-config-example.yaml file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9277 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; infected-file-handling: delete events: endpoint: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/invitations/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 15:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/invitations/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 # Autogenerated # Filename: invitations-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:0 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false http: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. File Search Query Language</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0020-file-search-query-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0020-file-search-query-language/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby, @kulmann, @felix-schwarz, @JammingBen Date: 2023-06-23 Context and Problem Statement From the users perspective, the interface to search is just a single form field where the user enters one or more search terms. The minimum expectation is that the search returns file names and links to files that:
have a file name that contains at least one of the search terms contain at least one of the search terms in the file contents have metadata that is equal or contains one of the search terms Decision Drivers The standard user should not be bothered by a query syntax The power user should also be able to narrow his search with an efficient and flexible syntax We need to consider different backend technologies which we need to access through an abstraction layer Using different indexing systems should lead to a slightly different feature set without changing the syntax completely Considered Options KQL - Keyword Query Language Simple Query Lucene Query Language Solr Query Language Elasticsearch Query Language Decision Outcome Chosen option: KQL - Keyword Query Language, because it enables advanced search across all platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conventions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/conventions/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to ownCloud Web Linting and Tests Changelog Items Code Conventions Early Returns Translations TypeScript Vue 3 and Composition API Dependencies This is a collection of tips and conventions to follow when working on the ownCloud web frontend. Since it is a living document, please open a PR if you find something missing.
Contributing to ownCloud Web Everyone is invited to contribute. Simply fork the codebase, check the issues for a suitable one and open a pull request!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDAV with Basic Authentication</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-basic-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-basic-auth/</guid>
      <description>WebDAV with Basic Authentication Basic Authentication is disabled by default in oCIS because of security considerations. In order to make the following Rclone commands work the oCIS administrator needs to enable Basic Authentication e.g. by setting the environment variable PROXY_ENABLE_BASIC_AUTH to true.
Please consider to use Rclone with OpenID Connect instead.
For the usage of a WebDAV remote with Rclone see also the Rclone documentation
Configure the WebDAV remote First of all we need to set up our credentials and the WebDAV remote for Rclone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDAV with OpenID Connect</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-oidc/</guid>
      <description>WebDAV with OpenID Connect Rclone itself is not able to open and maintain an OpenID Connect session. But it is able to still use OpenID Connect for authentication by leveraging a so called OIDC-agent.
Setting up the OIDC-agent You need to install the OIDC-agent from your OS&amp;rsquo; package repository (e.g. Debian or MacOS).
Configuring the OIDC-agent Run the following command to add a OpenID Connect profile to your OIDC-agent. It will open the login page of OpenID Connect identity provider where you need to log in if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an active session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/sse/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/sse/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 # Autogenerated # Filename: app-provider-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Information</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/additional-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/additional-information/</guid>
      <description>This section contains information on general topics
GRPC Maximum Message Size ocis is using grpc for inter-service communication. When having a folder with a lot of files (25.000+, the size does not matter) and doing a PROPFIND on that folder, the server will run into errors. This is because the grpc message body becomes to big. With introduction of the envvar OCIS_GRPC_MAX_RECEIVED_MESSAGE_SIZE, the max size for the grpc body can be raised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/building/</guid>
      <description>Frontend Backend Documentation As this project is built with Go and NodeJS, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go and NodeJS is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, NodeJS and Yarn, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.16. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:
git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building from source</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</guid>
      <description>Building ownCloud Web Updating dependencies Building the documentation Setting up Viewing the documentation Deploying the documentation Building ownCloud Web Run pnpm install to install dependencies Run pnpm build to build Web and all apps included in the packages folder Updating dependencies Run pnpm upgrade to update dependencies Building the documentation Setting up Install hugo Run make docs Viewing the documentation To view the rendered docs in the browser run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Ranges</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/port-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/port-ranges/</guid>
      <description>oCIS services often need a port to expose their services to other services or the outside world. As users may have many different extensions running on the same machine, we should track port usage in the oCIS ecosystem. In the best case we ensure that each extension uses a non colliding port range, to make life of users easier.
This page tracks the knowingly used port ranges.
Feel free to &amp;ldquo;reserve&amp;rdquo; a free port range when you&amp;rsquo;re developing an extension by adding your extension to the list (see the edit button in the top right corner).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-provider/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-provider/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 # Autogenerated # Filename: app-provider-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-registry/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/app-registry/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 # Autogenerated # Filename: app-registry-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/audit/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/audit/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 # Autogenerated # Filename: audit-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9229 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false events: endpoint: 127.0.0.1:9233 cluster: ocis-cluster tls_insecure: false tls_root_ca_certificate: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; enable_tls: false username: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; password: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; auditlog: log_to_console: true log_to_file: false filepath: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; format: json Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUDIT_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-basic/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-basic/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 # Autogenerated # Filename: auth-basic-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-bearer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-bearer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 # Autogenerated # Filename: auth-bearer-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9149 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-machine/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/auth-machine/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 # Autogenerated # Filename: auth-machine-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9167 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.0.0.1:9166 tls: null protocol: tcp token_manager: jwt_secret: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; reva: address: com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/eventhistory/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/eventhistory/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 # Autogenerated # Filename: eventhistory-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9270 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/frontend/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/frontend/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134 135 136 137 138 139 140 141 142 143 144 145 146 147 # Autogenerated # Filename: frontend-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/gateway/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/gateway/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 # Autogenerated # Filename: gateway-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/graph/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/graph/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134 135 136 137 138 139 140 141 142 143 144 # Autogenerated # Filename: graph-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/groups/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/groups/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 # Autogenerated # Filename: groups-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 # Autogenerated # Filename: idm-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9239 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false idm: ldaps_addr: 127.0.0.1:9235 cert: /var/lib/ocis/idm/ldap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/idp/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/idp/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 # Autogenerated # Filename: idp-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/nats/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/nats/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 # Autogenerated # Filename: nats-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9234 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false nats: host: 127.0.0.1 port: 9233 clusterid: ocis-cluster store_dir: /var/lib/ocis/nats tls_cert: /var/lib/ocis/nats/tls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/notifications/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/notifications/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 # Autogenerated # Filename: notifications-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocdav/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocdav/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 # Autogenerated # Filename: ocdav-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 # Autogenerated # Filename: ocm-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocs/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocs/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 # Autogenerated # Filename: ocs-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/policies/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/policies/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 # Autogenerated # Filename: policies-config-example.yaml grpc: addr: 127.0.0.1:9125 tls: null debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9129 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false events: endpoint: 127.0.0.1:9233 cluster: ocis-cluster tls_insecure: false tls_root_ca_certificate: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; enable_tls: false username: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; password: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; grpc_client_tls: null log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; engine: timeout: 10s policies: [] mimes: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; postprocessing: query: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description POLICIES_GRPC_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/postprocessing/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/postprocessing/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 # Autogenerated # Filename: postprocessing-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9255 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false store: store: memory nodes: [] database: postprocessing table: postprocessing ttl: 0s size: 0 username: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; password: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; postprocessing: events: endpoint: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/proxy/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/proxy/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134 135 136 137 138 139 140 141 142 143 144 145 146 147 148 149 150 151 152 153 154 155 156 157 158 159 160 161 162 163 164 165 166 167 168 169 170 171 172 173 # Autogenerated # Filename: proxy-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/search/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/search/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 # Autogenerated # Filename: search-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 # Autogenerated # Filename: settings-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/sharing/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/sharing/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 # Autogenerated # Filename: sharing-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-publiclink/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-publiclink/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 # Autogenerated # Filename: storage-publiclink-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9179 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-shares/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-shares/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 # Autogenerated # Filename: storage-shares-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9156 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-system/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-system/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 # Autogenerated # Filename: storage-system-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-users/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/storage-users/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 # Autogenerated # Filename: storage-users-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/store/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/store/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 # Autogenerated # Filename: store-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.0.0.1:9464 token: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pprof: false zpages: false grpc: addr: 127.0.0.1:9460 tls: null grpc_client_tls: null data_path: /var/lib/ocis/store Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/thumbnails/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/thumbnails/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 # Autogenerated # Filename: thumbnails-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/userlog/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/userlog/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 # Autogenerated # Filename: userlog-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/users/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/users/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 # Autogenerated # Filename: users-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/web/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/web/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118 119 120 121 122 123 124 125 126 127 128 129 130 131 132 133 134 135 136 137 138 139 140 141 142 143 144 145 146 # Autogenerated # Filename: web-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/webdav/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/webdav/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 # Autogenerated # Filename: webdav-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/webfinger/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/webfinger/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 # Autogenerated # Filename: webfinger-config-example.yaml tracing: enabled: false type: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; endpoint: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; collector: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; log: level: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; pretty: false color: false file: &amp;#34;&amp;#34; debug: addr: 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Hints</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/configuration_hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/idm/configuration_hints/</guid>
      <description>TLS Server Certificates By default IDM generates a self-signed certificate and key on first startup to be able to provide TLS protected services. The certificate is stored in idm/ldap.crt inside the oCIS base data directory. The key is in idm/ldap.key in the same directory. You can use a custom server certificate by setting the IDM_LDAPS_CERT and IDM_LDAPS_KEY.
Default / Demo Users On startup IDM creates a set of default services users that are needed internally to provide access to IDM to other oCIS services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/spaces/</guid>
      <description>Spaces API Example Space Creating Spaces Create a single space POST /drives Reading Spaces List all spaces GET /drives List My Spaces GET /me/drives List my spaces with filters GET /me/drives/$filter=&amp;lt;attribute&amp;gt; &amp;lt;comparison operator&amp;gt; &amp;lt;value&amp;gt; Example filters List my spaces with ordering GET /me/drives/$orderby=&amp;lt;key&amp;gt; &amp;lt;order&amp;gt; Ordering examples Modifying Spaces Set the space quota to 5GB PATCH /drives/{drive-id} Change the space name, subtitle and alias PATCH /drives/{drive-id} Disabling / Deleting Spaces Disable a space DELETE /drives/{drive-id} Restore a space PATCH /drives/{drive-id} Permanently delete a space DELETE /drives/{drive-id} Spaces API The Spaces API is implementing a subset of the functionality of the MS Graph Drives resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theming</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/idp/theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/idp/theming/</guid>
      <description>Intro Customizing assets Static assets CSS Containers What pages to theme Components Images Locales Building assets Intro Our default IDP UI is built with the LibreGraph Connect React app. Even though this app comes already with a simple theming options, we have compiled our own edited version of the app with more advanced changes than the default theming offers. Because of that, it is not possible at the moment to do any kind of easy theming and including custom theme means again compiling custom assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OIDC</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/identity-provider/oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/identity-provider/oidc/</guid>
      <description>Infinite Scale has implemented OpenID Connect (OIDC) for authentication. OIDC defines a discovery mechanism, called OpenID Connect Discovery, where an OpenID server publishes its metadata at a well-known URL, typically:
https://ocis.test/.well-known/openid-configuration
This URL returns a JSON listing of the OpenID/OAuth endpoints, supported scopes and claims, public keys used to sign the tokens, and other details. The clients can use this information to construct a request to the OpenID server. The field names and values are defined in the OpenID Connect Discovery Specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Upload</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/tus_upload/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/tus_upload/</guid>
      <description>Infinite Scale supports the tus resumable-upload protocol, which is a robust, modular, and open protocol designed to resume large file uploads reliably over HTTP. In situations where file uploads might be interrupted due to network issues, browser crashes, or other unforeseen interruptions, tus ensures that uploads can be resumed from the point of failure without losing data. This documentation shows some basic examples, refer tus official site for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21. Service accounts</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0021-service-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0021-service-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @C0rby Date: 2023-01-18 Context and Problem Statement There are three levels of security checks in a microservice web application that uses OpenID Connect:
scope claims limit the possible operations to what the user (or admin on behalf of the organization) consented to service authorization limit the possible operations to what specific services are allowed to do, on behalf of users or even without them permission checks limit the possible operations to the relationships between subject, permission and resource allow This ADR deals with a prerequisite for service authorization: service accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22. Sharing and Space Management API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0022-sharing-and-space-management-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 02:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0022-sharing-and-space-management-api/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @jammingben @butonic @theonering @kobergj @micbar Date: 2023-08-08 Technical Story: Public issue
Context and Problem Statement In the early days of the rewrite of ownCloud it was an important goal to keep all important APIs compatible with ownCloud 10. Infinite Scale embraced that goal until version 1.0.0.
After that first release, the focus changed.
Infinite Scale started the spaces feature which brings a whole new set of APIs and concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23. Index and store metadata</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0023-index-and-store-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 15:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0023-index-and-store-metadata/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @dschmidt, @micbar, @dragotin Date: 2023-10-17 Context and Problem Statement ownCloud Infinite Scale is supposed to become a data platform and as such it needs to provide access to metadata. Currently only metadata common to all file types (filesize, mime-type, &amp;hellip;) is stored in the index and the metadata storage. We want to make other file type specific metadata available to consumers of our internal and external APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Hello extension</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_hello/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik Local setup Overview oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy oCIS Hello extension runs beside the main oCIS stack and providing the Hello functionality Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists of 3 containers. One of them is Traefik, a proxy which is terminating SSL and forwards the requests to oCIS in the internal docker network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Keycloak</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_keycloak/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik Local setup Overview oCIS and Keycloak running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Keycloak acting as the IDP for oCIS Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists 4 containers. One of them is Traefik, a proxy which is terminating ssl and forwards the requests to oCIS in the internal docker network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with LDAP</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_ldap/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install this example Local setup Overview Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup OpenLDAP server with demo users LDAP admin interface to edit users oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy oCIS is using the LDAP server as user backend Find this example on GitHub
Server Deployment Requirements Linux server with docker and docker-compose installed four domains set up and pointing to your server ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with S3 storage backend (MinIO)</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_s3/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik Local setup Overview oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy MinIO as S3 compatible storage provider oCIS is configured to use S3 as user storage provider Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists 3 containers. One of them is Traefik, a proxy which is terminating SSL and forwards the requests to oCIS in the internal docker network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Traefik</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_traefik/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik Local setup Overview oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists of three containers. One of them is Traefik, a proxy which is terminating ssl and forwards the requests to oCIS in the internal docker network.
The other one is oCIS itself running all extensions in one container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with WOPI server</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_wopi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_wopi/</guid>
      <description>Overview Overview Image Server Deployment Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik Local setup Local setup for web development Overview oCIS, Wopi server, Collabora and OnlyOffice running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Collabora and OnlyOffice enable you to edit documents in your browser Wopi server acts as a bridge to make the oCIS storage accessible to Collabora and OnlyOffice Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup Find this example on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel deployment of oC10 and oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/oc10_ocis_parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/oc10_ocis_parallel/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment Requirements Install this example Local setup Overview This setup reflects stage 6 of the oC10 to oCIS migration plan Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup OpenLDAP server with demo users LDAP admin interface to edit users Keycloak as OpenID Connect provider in federation with the LDAP server ownCloud 10 with MariaDB and Redis ownCloud 10 is configured to synchronize users from the LDAP server ownCloud 10 is used to use OpenID Connect for authentication with Keycloak oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy oCIS is using the ownCloudSQL storage driver on the same files and same database as ownCloud 10 oCIS is using Keycloak as OpenID Connect provider oCIS is using the LDAP server as user backend All requests to both oCIS and oC10 are routed through the oCIS proxy and will be routed based on an OIDC claim to one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>What is Kubernetes References and further reads How does oCIS fit in the Kubernetes model What is Minikube What is kubectl What are Helm Charts, and why they are useful for oCIS Installing Helm Setting up Minikube oCIS charts Run oCIS What is Kubernetes Formally described as:
Kubernetes is a portable, extensible, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation.
source
Without getting too deep in definitions, and for the purpose of compactness, Kubernetes can be summarized as a way of managing containers that run applications to ensure that there is no downtime and an optimal usage of resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing ownCloud Web Versioning Release Guide Next steps Releasing ownCloud Web OwnCloud Web can be hosted standalone, as part of oCIS or as ownCloud 10 app (Web UI versions &amp;lt; 7.1.0).
Versioning We follow the Semantic Versioning scheme. Therefore, each change is of one of the possible types: Bugfix, Change, Enhancement, Security.
The highest type before a new release determines the version update number, so if it&amp;rsquo;s only Bugfix and Security changes the next release will be a PATCH version bump, if there&amp;rsquo;s at least one Enhancement within the changes this leads to a MINOR version bump, while Change type changes make for a new MAJOR release version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload processing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/upload-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 12:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/upload-processing/</guid>
      <description>Uploads are handled by a dedicated service that uses TUS.io for resumable uploads. When all bytes have been transferred the upload is finalized by making the file available in file listings and for download.
The finalization may be asynchronous when mandatory workflow steps are involved.
Legacy PUT upload %%{init: {&#34;sequence&#34;: { &#34;showSequenceNumbers&#34;:true, &#34;messageFontFamily&#34;:&#34;courier&#34;, &#34;messageFontWeight&#34;:&#34;normal&#34;, &#34;messageFontSize&#34;:&#34;11&#34;}}}%% %% font weight is a css bug: https://github.com/mermaid-js/mermaid/issues/1976 %% edit this diagram by pasting it into eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol changes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/protocol-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 08:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/protocol-changes/</guid>
      <description>The spaces concept allows clients to look up the space endpoints a user has access to and then do individual sync discoveries. Technically, we introduce an indirection that allows clients to rely on server provided URLs instead of hardcoded /webdav or /dav/files/{username} paths, that may change over time.
Space discovery %%{init: {&#34;sequence&#34;: { &#34;showSequenceNumbers&#34;:true, &#34;messageFontFamily&#34;:&#34;courier&#34;, &#34;messageFontWeight&#34;:&#34;normal&#34;, &#34;messageFontSize&#34;:&#34;11&#34;}}}%% %% font weight is a css bug: https://github.com/mermaid-js/mermaid/issues/1976 %% edit this diagram by pasting it into eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services Communication</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/services-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/services-communication/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repo structure and (published) packages</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/repo-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/repo-structure/</guid>
      <description>Repository Structure dev Folder and docker-compose.yml File docs Folder packages Folder tests Folder package.json File vite.config.ts (Published) Packages Code Style and Build Config ownCloud Design System web-client web-pkg web-runtime Standalone Core Apps Viewer and Editor Apps Repository Structure From a developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, the most important parts of the ownCloud Web repo are the following files and folders:
dev Folder and docker-compose.yml File The /dev folder contains all the configuration files that are needed in the docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cephfs</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</guid>
      <description>Development Architecture Implemented Aspects Future work oCIS intends to make the aspects of existing storage systems available as transparently as possible, but the static sync algorithm of the desktop client relies on some form of recursive change time propagation on the server side to detect changes. While this can be bolted on top of existing file systems with inotify, the kernel audit or a fuse based overlay filesystem, a storage system that already implements this aspect is preferable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decomposed FS on NFS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</guid>
      <description>NFS Server Setup NFS Client Mount oCIS Start using the NFS Share oCIS&amp;rsquo; default storage backend is the Decomposed FS. The Decomposed FS can be set up to run on a NFS share. That way the same storage can be provided over the network to other nodes running oCIS.
This document summarizes a few important considerations of the NFS setup and describes a tested setup. The test has not covered concurrent access of data from different nodes yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Stat Polling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/efficient-stat-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/efficient-stat-polling/</guid>
      <description>The fallback sync mechanism uses the ETag to determine which part of a sync tree needs to be checked by recursively descending into folders whose ETag has changed. The ETag can be calculated using a stat() call in the filesystem and we are going to explore how many stat() calls are necessary and how the number might be reduced.
ETag propagation What does ETag propagation mean? Whenever a file changes its content or metadata the ETag or &amp;ldquo;entity tag&amp;rdquo; changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Current status How to do it Install the owncloud 10 graphapi app Enable the graphapi app Grab ocis! Start ocis glauth configure it Run it! Check it is up and running Start ocis storage-gateway, storage-authbasic and storage-userprovider Start ocis storage-userprovider Start ocis idp Set environment variables Run it! Check it is up and running Start ocis proxy Start ocis-web Run it! Patch owncloud Install the owncloud 10 openidconnect app Next steps We are planning to build a bridge from ownCloud 10 to ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build/</guid>
      <description>Build requirements Get the sources Build the oCIS binary Build a local oCIS docker image Build requirements see Development - Getting Started
Get the sources git clone https://github.com/owncloud/ocis.git cd ocis Build the oCIS binary You only need to run following command if you have changed protobuf definitions or the frontend part in one of the extensions. Run the command in the root directory of the repository. Otherwise you can skip this step and proceed to build the oCIS binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</guid>
      <description>Docker dev environment for eos storage 1. Start eos &amp;amp; ocis containers 2. LDAP support 3. Home storage 4. Users storage 5. Metadata storage 6. Accounts service Verification Further exploration Cleaning up Troubleshooting Docker-compose exits right away Where are the logs ? How do I update a service in the ocis container? Creation and upload of files does not work Uploading big files appears to hang Running out of space quickly oCIS can be configured to run on top of eos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invitation flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/invitation_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/invitation_flow/</guid>
      <description> OCM Invitation Flow sequenceDiagram box Instance A participant ima as InviteManager A participant gwa as Gateway A participant httpa as HTTP Api A (ocm, sm) end actor usera as User A actor userb as User B box Instance B participant httpb as HTTP Api B (ocm, sm) participant gwb as Gateway B participant imb as InviteManager B end Note over usera: A creates invitation token usera-&gt;&gt;+httpa: POST /generate-invite (sciencemesh) httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: GenerateInviteToken gwa-&gt;&gt;+ima: GenerateInviteToken Note left of ima: store token in repo ima--&gt;&gt;-gwa: return token gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return token httpa--&gt;&gt;-usera: return token Note over usera,userb: A passes token to B Note over userb: B accepts invitation userb-&gt;&gt;+httpb: POST /accept-invite (sciencemesh) httpb-&gt;&gt;+gwb: ForwardInvite gwb-&gt;&gt;+imb: ForwardInvite imb-&gt;&gt;+httpa: POST /invite-accepted (ocm) httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: AcceptInvite gwa-&gt;&gt;+ima: AcceptInvite Note left of ima: get token from repo Note left of ima: add remote user ima--&gt;&gt;-gwa: return gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return remote user httpa-&gt;&gt;-imb: return remote user Note right of imb: add remote user imb--&gt;&gt;-gwb: return gwb--&gt;&gt;-httpb: return httpb--&gt;&gt;-userb: return </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/users/</guid>
      <description>Users API Reading users GET /me GET /users GET /users?$expand=memberOf GET /users/{userid or accountname} GET /users/{userid or accountname}?$expand=memberOf Creating / Updating Users POST /users Request Body Response DELETE /users/{id} PATCH /users/{id} Change password POST /me/changePassword Request Body Users API The Users API is implementing a subset of the functionality of the MS Graph User resource The JSON representation of a User handled by the Users API looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta testplan</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/beta-testplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/beta-testplan/</guid>
      <description>Beta Testing This document is supposed to give you some ideas how and what to test on ocis. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to be an extensive list of all tests to be done, rather it should help you, as beta-tester, to get started and enable you to get creative and create your own test-cases. Derive from these examples, be creative, do unusual and unconventional things, to try to break things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/testing/</guid>
      <description>Testing With Test Suite in Docker Run Full Test Suite Local oCIS Tests (prefix api) Tests Transferred From ownCloud Core (prefix coreApi) Run Single Feature Test oCIS Image to Be Tested (Skip Local Image Build) Test Log Output Cleanup Testing With Test Suite Natively Installed Run oCIS Run Local oCIS Tests (prefix api) Run Tests Transferred From ownCloud Core (prefix coreApi) Use Existing Tests for BDD Running ENV Config Tests (@env-Config) Run oCIS With ociswrapper Run the Tests Writing New ENV Config Tests Running Test Suite With Email Service (@email) Setup Inbucket Run oCIS Run the Acceptance Test Running Test Suite With Tika Service (@tikaServiceNeeded) Setup Tika Service Run oCIS Run the Acceptance Test Running Tests for Parallel Deployment Setup the Parallel Deployment Environment Getting the Test Helpers Run the Acceptance Tests Running Test Suite With Antivirus Service (@antivirus) Setup clamAV 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage/spaces/</guid>
      <description>Editing a Storage Space Updating a space property Updating a space description Quotas Quota Enforcement Considerations Storage Spaces Shares Notes Editing a Storage Space The OData specification allows for a mirage of ways of addressing an entity. We will support addressing a Drive entity by its unique identifier, which is the one the graph-api returns when listing spaces, and its format is:
{ &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1284d238-aa92-42ce-bdc4-0b0000009157!b6e2c9cc-9dbe-42f0-b522-4f2d3e175e9c&amp;#34; } This is an extract of an element of the list spaces response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/tooling/</guid>
      <description>Packaging Development Setup Prerequisites Installing Dependencies Starting the Server Building and Accessing Web Using Instant Hot-Reload via Vite Running Web with oC10 Packaging Web is using pnpm as package manager and vite as build tool. The latter is built on top of rollup and brings some additional features such as instant hot-reloading.
Development Setup Prerequisites docker docker-compose (if not already included in your docker installation) pnpm node If youre not using Docker Desktop, you might have to modify your /etc/hosts and add 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Registry Discovery</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In order for an oCIS client to access oCIS storage spaces for an End-User, the client needs to know where the oCIS instance is. oCIS uses WebFinger RFC7033 to locate the oCIS instance for an End-User.
This discovery is optional. If the client has another way of discovering the OpenID instance, e.g. when logging in with a username a static domain might be configured or the domain in the URL might be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</guid>
      <description>Compatibility Prerequisites Setting up the ownCloud Server Adjusting config.php Setting up OAuth2 Setting up Web Running Web Running acceptance tests Compatibility Please note that the usage of Web UI and ownCloud 10 as backend is not recommended starting with version 7.1.0 of the Web UI. Therefore, this section only applies to versions &amp;lt; 7.1.0.
Prerequisites Decide on which host and port Web will be served, for example https://web-host:9100/web-path/. In this document, we will refer to the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/extensions/</guid>
      <description>oCIS is all about files, sync and share - but most of the time there is more you want to do with your files, e.g. having a different view on your photo collection or editing your offices files in an online file editor. ownCloud 10 faced the same problem and solved it with applications, which can extend the functionality of ownCloud 10 in a wide range. Since oCIS is different in its architecture compared to ownCloud 10, we had to come up with a similar (yet slightly different) solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Share Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/create_share_flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/ocm/create_share_flow/</guid>
      <description> OCM Create Share Flow sequenceDiagram box Instance A participant osp as ocmsharesprovider participant gwa as Gateway A participant httpa as ocs end actor usera as User A box Instance B participant httpb as ocmd participant gwb as Gateway B participant ocmc as OCMCore end Note over usera: A shares a resource with B usera-&gt;&gt;+httpa: CreateShare httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: GetInfoByDomain Note left of gwa: GetInfoByDomain(ocmproviderauthorizer) gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: GetAcceptedUser Note left of gwa: GetAcceptedUser(ocminvitemanager) gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: CreateOCMShare gwa-&gt;&gt;+osp: CreateOCMShare osp-&gt;&gt;+gwa: Stat gwa--&gt;&gt;-osp: return Note left of osp: store share in repo osp-&gt;&gt;+httpb: POST /shares httpb-&gt;&gt;+gwb: IsProviderAllowed Note right of gwb: IsProviderAllowed(ocmproviderauthorizer) gwb--&gt;&gt;-httpb: return httpb-&gt;&gt;+gwb: GetUser Note right of gwb: GetUser(userprovider) gwb--&gt;&gt;-httpb: return httpb-&gt;&gt;+gwb: CreateOCMCoreShare gwb-&gt;&gt;+ocmc: CreateOCMCoreShare Note right of ocmc: StoreReceivedShare ocmc--&gt;&gt;-gwb: return gwb--&gt;&gt;-httpb: return httpb--&gt;&gt;-osp: return osp--&gt;&gt;-gwa: return gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return httpa-&gt;&gt;+gwa: Stat Note left of gwa: Stat(storageprovider) gwa--&gt;&gt;-httpa: return httpa--&gt;&gt;-usera: return </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authorization</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/authorization/</guid>
      <description>In its default configuration, Infinite Scale supports three authentication methods as outlined on the OIDC official site:
Authorization Code Flow Implicit Flow Hybrid Flow For detailed information on Infinite Scale&amp;rsquo;s support for OpenID Connect (OIDC), please consult the OIDC section. To authenticate a client app using OIDC, both client_id and client_secret are essential. Infinite Scale does not offer dynamic registration. The required data for the default ownCloud clients can be found in the link and are availble for the following apps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/http/graph/groups/</guid>
      <description>Groups API Reading groups GET /groups GET /groups?$expand=members GET /groups/{groupid} GET /groups/{groupid}?$expand=members Getting Group Members GET /groups/{groupid}/members Creating / Updating Groups POST /groups Request Body Response DELETE /groups/{id} PATCH /groups/{id} Adding a single member to a group POST /groups/{id}/members/$ref Adding multiple members in a single request PATCH /groups/{id} Removing a member DELETE /groups/{groupid}/members/{id}/$ref Groups API The Groups API is implementing a subset of the functionality of the MS Graph Group resource The JSON representation of a Group as handled by the Groups API looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/web/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/web/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing Package Hierarchy Prerequisites Updating ocis-web Releasing The next generation Web Frontend is shipped as an oCIS Extension. The ocis-web extension is also embedded in the single binary and part of the ocis server command.
To update this package within all the deliveries, we need to update the package in the following chain from the bottom to the top.
Package Hierarchy ocis ocis-web ocis-pkg ownCloud Web Prerequisites Before updating the assets, make sure that ownCloud Web has been released first and take note of its release tag name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 16:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</guid>
      <description>The migration happens in subsequent stages while the service is online. First all users need to migrate to the new architecture, then the global namespace needs to be introduced. Finally, the data on disk can be migrated user by user by switching the storage driver.
@jfd: It might be easier to introduce the spaces api in oc10 and then migrate to oCIS. We cannot migrate both at the same time, the architecture to oCIS (which will change fileids) and introduce a global namespace (which requires stable fileids to let clients handle moves without redownloading).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Login Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</guid>
      <description>Login Flow The following sequence diagram describes the openid connect auth code flow. The eight numbered steps and notes correspond to the openid connect auth code flow steps. Example requests are based on the spec as well:
sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ %% this documents the login workflow %% examples taken from the oidc spec https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#CodeFlowAuth %% TODO add PKCE, see https://developer.okta.com/blog/2019/08/22/okta-authjs-pkce#use-pkce-to-make-your-apps-more-secure participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant glauth as ocis-glauth participant graph as ocis-graph participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as external LDAP server user-&gt;&gt;+client: What is the content of my home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</guid>
      <description> Metrics This service provides some Prometheus metrics through the debug endpoint, you can optionally secure the metrics endpoint by some random token, which has to be configured either through the flag --debug-token or the environment variable OCIS_DEBUG_TOKEN mentioned above. By default, the metrics endpoint is bound to http://0.0.0.0:8001/metrics.
go_gc_duration_seconds A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_sum A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_count A summary of the GC invocation durations go_goroutines Number of goroutines that currently exist go_info Information about the Go environment go_memstats_alloc_bytes Number of bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_alloc_bytes_total Total number of bytes allocated, even if freed go_memstats_buck_hash_sys_bytes Number of bytes used by the profiling bucket hash table go_memstats_frees_total Total number of frees go_memstats_gc_cpu_fraction The fraction of this program&amp;rsquo;s available CPU time used by the GC since the program started go_memstats_gc_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for garbage collection system metadata go_memstats_heap_alloc_bytes Number of heap bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_heap_idle_bytes Number of heap bytes waiting to be used go_memstats_heap_inuse_bytes Number of heap bytes that are in use go_memstats_heap_objects Number of allocated objects go_memstats_heap_released_bytes Number of heap bytes released to OS go_memstats_heap_sys_bytes Number of heap bytes obtained from system go_memstats_last_gc_time_seconds Number of seconds since 1970 of last garbage collection go_memstats_lookups_total Total number of pointer lookups go_memstats_mallocs_total Total number of mallocs go_memstats_mcache_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mcache structures go_memstats_mcache_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mcache structures obtained from system go_memstats_mspan_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mspan structures go_memstats_mspan_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mspan structures obtained from system go_memstats_next_gc_bytes Number of heap bytes when next garbage collection will take place go_memstats_other_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for other system allocations go_memstats_stack_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by the stack allocator go_memstats_stack_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system for stack allocator go_memstats_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system go_threads Number of OS threads created promhttp_metric_handler_requests_in_flight Current number of scrapes being served promhttp_metric_handler_requests_total Total number of scrapes by HTTP status code </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</guid>
      <description>Request Flow The following sequence diagram describes the general request flow. It shows where account provisioning and token minting are happening:
sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as corporate LDAP server user-&gt;&gt;+client: What is the content of my home? client-&gt;&gt;+proxy: PROPFIND Bearer auth using oidc auth token Note over client,proxy: What is in a bearer token?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public upload Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</guid>
      <description>Public Upload flow The following diagram describes the flow of requests:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.eventhistory.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_eventhistory_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_eventhistory_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto Event Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto Event Field Type Label Description type string REQUIRED. id string REQUIRED. event bytes REQUIRED Scalar Value Types .proto Type Notes C++ Java double double double float float float int32 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers  if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint32 instead. int32 int int64 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers  if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint64 instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.policies.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_policies_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_policies_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/policies/v0/policies.proto Environment Request Resource Resource.ID User User.ID Stage Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/policies/v0/policies.proto Environment Field Type Label Description stage Stage user User request Request resource Resource Request Field Type Label Description method string path string Resource Field Type Label Description id Resource.ID name string size uint64 url string Resource.ID Field Type Label Description storage_id string opaque_id string space_id string User Field Type Label Description id User.ID username string mail string display_name string groups string repeated User.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto Audio Entity GeoCoordinates Match Reference ResourceID Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto Audio Field Type Label Description album string optional albumArtist string optional artist string optional bitrate int64 optional composers string optional copyright string optional disc int32 optional discCount int32 optional duration int64 optional genre string optional hasDrm bool optional isVariableBitrate bool optional title string optional track int32 optional trackCount int32 optional year int32 optional Entity Field Type Label Description ref Reference id ResourceID name string etag string size uint64 last_modified_time google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto Bool Bundle Identifier Int ListOption ListOptionValue ListValue MultiChoiceList Permission Resource Setting SingleChoiceList String UserRoleAssignment Value ValueWithIdentifier Bundle.Type Permission.Constraint Permission.Operation Resource.Type Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto Bool Field Type Label Description default bool @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; label string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;label&amp;rdquo; Bundle Field Type Label Description id string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;id&amp;rdquo; name string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; type Bundle.Type @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo; extension string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;extension&amp;rdquo; display_name string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;display_name&amp;rdquo; settings Setting repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;settings&amp;rdquo; resource Resource @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;resource&amp;rdquo; Identifier Field Type Label Description extension string bundle string setting string Int Field Type Label Description default int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; min int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;min&amp;rdquo; max int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;max&amp;rdquo; step int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;step&amp;rdquo; placeholder string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;placeholder&amp;rdquo; ListOption Field Type Label Description value ListOptionValue @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; default bool @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; display_value string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;display_value&amp;rdquo; ListOptionValue Field Type Label Description string_value string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;string_value&amp;rdquo; int_value int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;int_value&amp;rdquo; ListValue Field Type Label Description values ListOptionValue repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo; MultiChoiceList Field Type Label Description options ListOption repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;options&amp;rdquo; Permission Field Type Label Description operation Permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto DeleteOptions Field ListOptions ReadOptions ReadOptions.WhereEntry Record Record.MetadataEntry WriteOptions Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto DeleteOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string Field Field Type Label Description type string type of value e.g string, int, int64, bool, float64 value string the actual value ListOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string prefix string suffix string limit uint64 offset uint64 ReadOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string prefix bool suffix bool limit uint64 offset uint64 where ReadOptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto CS3Source WebdavSource ThumbnailType Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto CS3Source Field Type Label Description path string authorization string WebdavSource Field Type Label Description url string REQUIRED. is_public_link bool REQUIRED. webdav_authorization string OPTIONAL. reva_authorization string OPTIONAL. public_link_token string OPTIONAL. ThumbnailType The file types to which the thumbnail can be encoded to.
Name Number Description PNG 0 Represents PNG type JPG 1 Represents JPG type GIF 2 Represents GIF type Scalar Value Types .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.eventhistory.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_eventhistory_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_eventhistory_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto GetEventsForUserRequest GetEventsRequest GetEventsResponse EventHistoryService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto GetEventsForUserRequest A request to retrieve events belonging to a userID
Field Type Label Description userID string the userID of the events we want to get GetEventsRequest A request to retrieve events
Field Type Label Description ids string repeated the ids of the events we want to get GetEventsResponse The service response
Field Type Label Description events ocis.messages.eventhistory.v0.Event repeated EventHistoryService A Service for storing events</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.policies.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_policies_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_policies_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/policies/v0/policies.proto EvaluateRequest EvaluateResponse policiesProvider Scalar Value Types ocis/services/policies/v0/policies.proto EvaluateRequest Field Type Label Description query string environment ocis.messages.policies.v0.Environment EvaluateResponse Field Type Label Description result bool policiesProvider Method Name Request Type Response Type Description Evaluate EvaluateRequest EvaluateResponse Scalar Value Types .proto Type Notes C++ Java double double double float float float int32 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers  if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint32 instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto IndexSpaceRequest IndexSpaceResponse SearchIndexRequest SearchIndexResponse SearchRequest SearchResponse IndexProvider SearchProvider Scalar Value Types ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto IndexSpaceRequest Field Type Label Description space_id string user_id string IndexSpaceResponse SearchIndexRequest Field Type Label Description page_size int32 Optional. The maximum number of entries to return in the response page_token string Optional. A pagination token returned from a previous call to Get
that indicates from where search should continue query string ref ocis.messages.search.v0.Reference SearchIndexResponse Field Type Label Description matches ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto AddSettingToBundleRequest AddSettingToBundleResponse AssignRoleToUserRequest AssignRoleToUserResponse GetBundleRequest GetBundleResponse GetPermissionByIDRequest GetPermissionByIDResponse GetValueByUniqueIdentifiersRequest GetValueRequest GetValueResponse ListBundlesRequest ListBundlesResponse ListPermissionsByResourceRequest ListPermissionsByResourceResponse ListPermissionsRequest ListPermissionsResponse ListRoleAssignmentsRequest ListRoleAssignmentsResponse ListValuesRequest ListValuesResponse RemoveRoleFromUserRequest RemoveSettingFromBundleRequest SaveBundleRequest requests and responses for settings bundles SaveBundleResponse SaveValueRequest SaveValueResponse BundleService PermissionService RoleService ValueService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto AddSettingToBundleRequest Field Type Label Description bundle_id string setting ocis.messages.settings.v0.Setting AddSettingToBundleResponse Field Type Label Description setting ocis.messages.settings.v0.Setting AssignRoleToUserRequest Field Type Label Description account_uuid string role_id string the role_id is a bundle_id internally AssignRoleToUserResponse Field Type Label Description assignment ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto DatabasesRequest DatabasesResponse DeleteRequest DeleteResponse ListRequest ListResponse ReadRequest ReadResponse TablesRequest TablesResponse WriteRequest WriteResponse Store Scalar Value Types ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto DatabasesRequest DatabasesResponse Field Type Label Description databases string repeated DeleteRequest Field Type Label Description key string options ocis.messages.store.v0.DeleteOptions DeleteResponse ListRequest Field Type Label Description options ocis.messages.store.v0.ListOptions ListResponse Field Type Label Description keys string repeated ReadRequest Field Type Label Description key string options ocis.messages.store.v0.ReadOptions ReadResponse Field Type Label Description records ocis.messages.store.v0.Record repeated TablesRequest Field Type Label Description database string TablesResponse Field Type Label Description tables string repeated WriteRequest Field Type Label Description record ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 11:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto GetThumbnailRequest GetThumbnailResponse ThumbnailService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto GetThumbnailRequest A request to retrieve a thumbnail
Field Type Label Description filepath string The path to the source image thumbnail_type ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.ThumbnailType The type to which the thumbnail should get encoded to. width int32 The width of the thumbnail height int32 The height of the thumbnail processor string Indicates which image processor to use webdav_source ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.WebdavSource cs3_source ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.CS3Source GetThumbnailResponse The service response</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Bundles</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/bundles/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Bundle is a collection of settings, uniquely identified by the key of the extension registering the bundle and the key of the bundle itself. Its purpose is to let oCIS services define settings and make them available to users. They are dynamically rendered into forms, available in the frontend.
As of now we support five different types of settings:
boolean integer string single choice list of integers or strings multiple choice list of integers or strings Each Setting is uniquely identified by a key within the bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Web Running Web Setting up oCIS Start oCIS Running tests Setting up Web Clone the repository Initally install all dependencies by running pnpm install Copy ./config/config.json.sample-ocis to ./config/config.json and adjust values if required Running Web Start bundling web with a watcher by running pnpm build:w Setting up oCIS Setup oCIS by following the setup instructions Start oCIS with local links to your bundled web frontend and config by running WEB_ASSET_PATH=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/debugging/</guid>
      <description>Debugging Start ocis Use the debug binary and attach to the process as needed Start all services independently to replace one of them with a debug process Debugging the ocis in a docker container Gather error messages Managing dependencies and testing changes Debugging As a single binary for easy deployment running ocis server just forks itself to start all the services, which makes debugging those processes a little harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRPC API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/grpc/</guid>
      <description>hello.proto GreetRequest GreetResponse Hello Scalar Value Types hello.proto GreetRequest Field Type Label Description name string GreetResponse Field Type Label Description message string Hello Method Name Request Type Response Type Description Greet GreetRequest GreetResponse Scalar Value Types .proto Type Notes C++ Java double double double float float float int32 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers  if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint32 instead. int32 int int64 Uses variable-length encoding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/running/</guid>
      <description>In order to use the Hello extension we need to configure and start oCIS first. After that we can run the Hello extension itself.
Configure and start oCIS You can either start oCIS from a binary or build it from source.
No matter which way you choose, we need to create a configuration file for ownCloud Web, so that the Hello extension will be loaded in the frontend. Therefore create a file web-config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/settings/</guid>
      <description>oCIS provides an settings extension that other extensions can use to make settings accessible to users.
In case of the Hello extension administrator users are able to change the greeter message.
Settings are stored and presented to the user by the oCIS settings extension. It also exposes endpoints for registering and manipulating so called settings bundles.
The settings defined through settings bundles can be changed by authenticated users in ownCloud Web, if they have enough permissions to edit them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/testing/</guid>
      <description>This repository provides a general guideline for creating tests for an oCIS extension. The tests can be written in various levels from unit, integration, and end-to-end. It is not essential to write tests on all these levels as it can be redundant in some cases. This repository provides a reference for all levels of tests.
Unit tests Unit tests generally live inside *_test.go files in the /pkg directory. One such example in this extension is in /pkg/service/v0/service_test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Values</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/values/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Value is the value an authenticated user has chosen for a specific setting, defined in a settings bundle.
Identifying settings values A settings value is uniquely identified by four attributes. Three of them are coming from the definition of the setting within it&amp;rsquo;s settings bundle (see Settings Bundles for an example). The fourth identifies the user.
extension: Key of the extension that registered the settings bundle, bundleKey: Key of the settings bundle, settingKey: Key of the setting as defined within the bundle, accountUuid: The UUID of the authenticated user who has saved the setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 12:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/tracing/</guid>
      <description>By default, we use Jaeger for request tracing within oCIS. You can follow these steps to get started:
Start Jaeger by using the all-in-one docker image: docker run -d --name jaeger \ -e COLLECTOR_ZIPKIN_HTTP_PORT=9411 \ -p 5775:5775/udp \ -p 6831:6831/udp \ -p 6832:6832/udp \ -p 5778:5778 \ -p 16686:16686 \ -p 14268:14268 \ -p 14250:14250 \ -p 9411:9411 \ jaegertracing/all-in-one:1.17 Every single oCIS service has its own environment variables for enabling and configuring tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 12:32:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/profiling/</guid>
      <description>0. Prerequisites 1. Clone Reva 2. Patch reva with the area that you want sampled. 3. Replace reva in oCIS go.mod with local version and build a new binary 4. Build a new ocis binary 5. Start oCIS server 6. Run pprof Install pprof Collecting samples Room for improvement References 0. Prerequisites Go development kit of a supported version. Follow these instructions to install the go tool and set up GOPATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/actions/</guid>
      <description>Action extension type Configuration Action Action extension type Actions are one of the possible extension types. Registered actions get rendered in various places across the UI, depending on their scope and targets.
Configuration This is what the ActionExtension interface looks like:
interface ActionExtension { id: string type: &amp;#39;action&amp;#39; scopes?: ExtensionScope[] action: Action // Please check the Action section below } For id, type, and scopes, please see extension base section in top level docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folder View extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/folder-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/folder-view/</guid>
      <description>Folder view extension type The folder view is one of the possible extension types. Registered folder view can be used to render multiple resources (folders, files, spaces) in the UI.
Configuration This is what the FolderViewExtension interface looks like:
interface FolderViewExtension { id: string scopes?: ExtensionScope[] type: &amp;#39;folderView&amp;#39; folderView: FolderView // See FolderView section below } For id, type, and scopes, please see extension base section in top level docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left sidebar menu item extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/left-sidebar-menu-item/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/left-sidebar-menu-item/</guid>
      <description>Left sidebar menu item extension type Configuration AppNavigationItem Left sidebar menu item extension type One possible extension type is left sidebar menu items. Registered left sidebar menu items get rendered in the left sidebar, as long as there is more than one available.
Configuration To define a left sidebar menu item, you implement the SidebarNavExtension interface. It looks like this:
interface SidebarNavExtension { id: string type: &amp;#39;sidebarNav&amp;#39; scopes?: ExtensionScope[] navItem: AppNavigationItem // Please check the AppNavigationItem section below } } For id, type, and scopes, please see extension base section in top level docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Right sidebar panel extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/right-sidebar-panels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/right-sidebar-panels/</guid>
      <description>Extension Type SideBarPanel Configuration SideBarPanelContext SideBarPanel Extension Point FileSideBar Extension Type SideBarPanel The right sidebar is supposed to show information and make context specific actions available for single or multiple selected items.
It is structured in a hierarchical way:
Panels which are defined as root panels get rendered as immediate members of the right sidebar. Panels which are defined as non-root panels receive a navigation item below the root panels so that users can navigate into the respective sub panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/extension-system/extension-types/search/</guid>
      <description>Search extensions Configuration ListSearch PreviewSearch Search extensions One possible extension type is search. Registered search extensions are available when using the search field in the topbar. A search extension can consist of a list and a preview search. The result of a preview search is shown below the search input field while the list search result is
Configuration An example of a search extension configuration can be found below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running tests</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/testing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Unit Tests Unit Test File Structure E2E Tests (Playwright) Preparation Prepare &amp;amp; Start Web Run E2E Tests Options Acceptance Tests (Nightwatch) Preparation Prepare &amp;amp; Start Web Start Docker Run acceptance tests Watch the Test Run Analyze the Test Report Introduction In order to allow us to make changes quickly, often and with a high level of confidence, we heavily rely on tests within the web repository.
All the steps below require you to have the web repo cloned locally and dependencies installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/glossary/</guid>
      <description>In the context of this extension and oCIS in general, we are using the following terminology.
Configuration System configuration e.g. service host names and ports Changes need to be propagated to other services Typically modified on the CLI Settings Application level settings e.g. default language Can be modified at runtime without restarting the service Preferences User settings Subset of &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; e.g. preferred language of a user Settings Bundle Collection of related settings Registered by an oCIS extension Settings Value Manifestation of a setting for a specific user E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 08:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build-docs/</guid>
      <description>Build the documentation Add changes to the documentation Build the documentation For building the documentation you need to have Make and Go 1.14 or higher installed. Just run make -C docs docs-serve from within the root level of the oCIS git repository. This will make documentation available on localhost:1313 and also do a hot reload if you change something in the (non autogenerated) documentation files.
Add changes to the documentation Please keep this documentation in sync with the oCIS source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing ownCloud Infinite Scale at Ubernauten</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ubernauten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ubernauten/</guid>
      <description>Uberspace and ownCloud Infinite Scale in 50 seconds Three Steps to your Infinite UberSpace Service Management with Supervisord Updating ownCloud Infinite Scale Wiping and Clean Restart from Scratch Troubleshooting Uberspace and ownCloud Infinite Scale in 50 seconds This howto shows how to set up ownCloud Infinite Scale for a quick test. For convenience, we will use the free service from the Ubernauten &amp;ndash; Join us here: Uberspace Registration Page. They offer free of charge (for the first month) web hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a server</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/preparing_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/preparing_server/</guid>
      <description>Example for Hetzner Cloud Example for Hetzner Cloud create server on Hetzner Cloud. Set labels &amp;ldquo;owner&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;for&amp;rdquo;. Example for hcloud cli: hcloud server create --type cx21 --image ubuntu-20.04 --ssh-key admin --name ocis-server --label owner=admin --label for=testing
Configure DNS A-records for needed domains pointing on the servers ip address, for example in CloudFlare
Access server via ssh as root
Create a new user
$ adduser --disabled-password --gecos &amp;quot;&amp;quot; admin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/continuous-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/continuous-integration/</guid>
      <description>Concepts Things done in CI Flags in commit message and PR title Knowledge base oCIS uses DRONE as CI system. You can find the pipeline logs here or in your PR.
Concepts The pipeline is defined in Starlark and transformed to YAML upon pipeline run. This enables us to do a highly dynamic and non repeating pipeline configuration. We enforce Starlark format guidelines with Bazel Buildifier. You can format the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</guid>
      <description>The source code of the project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.
Stable, supported binary builds of ownCloud Infinite Scale that will be distributed by ownCloud GmbH are covered by a non OSS Freemium License EULA. This protects additional efforts that ownCloud GmbH is putting into these builds.
Since the source code of Infinite Scale is available under free licenses, the free usage can, should and will not be limited in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecating Variables</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/deprecating-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 15:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/deprecating-variables/</guid>
      <description>Deprecating Environment Variables Example What happens next? Deprecating Environment Variables Sometimes it is necessary to deprecate environment to align their naming with conventions. We therefore added annotations to automate the documentation process. It is necessary to know when the variable is going to be deprecated, when it is going to be removed and why.
Example // Notifications defines the config options for the notifications service. type Notifications struct { RevaGateway string `yaml:&amp;#34;reva_gateway&amp;#34; env:&amp;#34;OCIS_REVA_GATEWAY;REVA_GATEWAY&amp;#34; desc:&amp;#34;CS3 gateway used to look up user metadata&amp;#34; deprecationVersion:&amp;#34;3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</guid>
      <description>The Infinite Scale Release Notes have been moved and are published with the ownCloud Documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</guid>
      <description>You may have asked yourself why there are major version 1 tags in our GitHub repository but the Readme still states ownCloud Infinite Scale is currently in a technical preview state. It will be subject to a lot of changes and is not yet ready for general production deployments.. How can that be if it&amp;rsquo;s a major version 1?
Our initial and also our current plan is to stick to SemVer as versioning scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/getting-started/demo-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/getting-started/demo-users/</guid>
      <description>oCIS has the option to create demo users during the first startup. These enable you to do quick testing and developing.
To create the demo users, run the initial setup step with an additional environment variable. IDM_CREATE_DEMO_USERS=true ./bin/ocis server will generate the demo users listed in the table below. By default, it only generates the admin and one user for IDP and Reva respectively. Following users are available in the demo set:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/configuration/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/antivirus_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/antivirus_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_LOG_LEVELANTIVIRUS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level. Valid values are: &amp;lsquo;panic&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fatal&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;error&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;warn&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;info&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;debug&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;trace&amp;rsquo;. OCIS_LOG_PRETTYANTIVIRUS_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output. OCIS_LOG_COLORANTIVIRUS_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output. OCIS_LOG_FILEANTIVIRUS_LOG_FILE string The path to the log file. Activates logging to this file if set. ANTIVIRUS_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9277 Bind address of the debug server, where metrics, health, config and debug endpoints will be exposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/app-provider_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/app-provider_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description APP_PROVIDER_SERVICE_NAME string app-provider The name of the service. This needs to be changed when using more than one app provider. Each app provider configured needs to be identified by a unique service name. Possible examples are: &amp;lsquo;app-provider-collabora&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;app-provider-onlyoffice&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;app-provider-office365&amp;rsquo;. OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/app-registry_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/app-registry_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAPP_REGISTRY_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/audit_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/audit_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUDIT_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUDIT_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUDIT_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUDIT_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUDIT_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-basic_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-basic_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_BASIC_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-bearer_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-bearer_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_BEARER_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-machine_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-machine_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_MACHINE_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-service_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/auth-service_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_SERVICE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_SERVICE_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_SERVICE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_SERVICE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_SERVICE_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/clientlog_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/clientlog_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDCLIENTLOG_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPECLIENTLOG_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTCLIENTLOG_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORCLIENTLOG_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELCLIENTLOG_USERLOG_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/eventhistory_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/eventhistory_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDEVENTHISTORY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEEVENTHISTORY_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTEVENTHISTORY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOREVENTHISTORY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELEVENTHISTORY_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/frontend_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/frontend_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDFRONTEND_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEFRONTEND_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTFRONTEND_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORFRONTEND_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELFRONTEND_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/gateway_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/gateway_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGATEWAY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGATEWAY_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGATEWAY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGATEWAY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELGATEWAY_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/graph_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/graph_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGRAPH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGRAPH_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGRAPH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGRAPH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELGRAPH_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/groups_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/groups_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGROUPS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGROUPS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGROUPS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGROUPS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELGROUPS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/idm_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/idm_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDIDM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEIDM_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTIDM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORIDM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELIDM_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/idp_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/idp_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description IDP_PASSWORD_RESET_URI string The URI where a user can reset their password. OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDIDP_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEIDP_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTIDP_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORIDP_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/invitations_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/invitations_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDINVITATIONS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEINVITATIONS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTINVITATIONS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORINVITATIONS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELINVITATIONS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/nats_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/nats_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDNATS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPENATS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTNATS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORNATS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELNATS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/notifications_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/notifications_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDNOTIFICATIONS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPENOTIFICATIONS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTNOTIFICATIONS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORNOTIFICATIONS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocdav_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocdav_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEOCDAV_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTOCDAV_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOROCDAV_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELOCDAV_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocm_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocm_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEOCM_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTOCM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOROCM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELOCM_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocs_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/ocs_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEOCS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTOCS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOROCS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELOCS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/policies_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/policies_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description POLICIES_GRPC_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9125 The bind address of the GRPC service. POLICIES_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9129 Bind address of the debug server, where metrics, health, config and debug endpoints will be exposed. POLICIES_DEBUG_TOKEN string Token to secure the metrics endpoint. POLICIES_DEBUG_PPROF bool false Enables pprof, which can be used for profiling. POLICIES_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false Enables zpages, which can be used for collecting and viewing in-memory traces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/postprocessing_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/postprocessing_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDPOSTPROCESSING_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEPOSTPROCESSING_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTPOSTPROCESSING_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORPOSTPROCESSING_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELPOSTPROCESSING_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/proxy_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/proxy_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDPROXY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEPROXY_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTPROXY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORPROXY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELPROXY_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/search_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/search_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSEARCH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESEARCH_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSEARCH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSEARCH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSEARCH_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/settings_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/settings_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSETTINGS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESETTINGS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSETTINGS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSETTINGS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSETTINGS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/sharing_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/sharing_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSHARING_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESHARING_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSHARING_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSHARING_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSHARING_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/sse_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/sse_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_LOG_LEVELSSE_LOG_LEVEL string The log level. Valid values are: &amp;lsquo;panic&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fatal&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;error&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;warn&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;info&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;debug&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;trace&amp;rsquo;. OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSSE_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output. OCIS_LOG_COLORSSE_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output. OCIS_LOG_FILESSE_LOG_FILE string The path to the log file. Activates logging to this file if set. SSE_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9135 Bind address of the debug server, where metrics, health, config and debug endpoints will be exposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-publiclink_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-publiclink_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-shares_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-shares_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_SHARES_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-system_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-system_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_SYSTEM_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-users_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/storage-users_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_USERS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/store_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/store_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORE_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORE_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/thumbnails_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/thumbnails_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPETHUMBNAILS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELTHUMBNAILS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/userlog_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/userlog_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDUSERLOG_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEUSERLOG_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTUSERLOG_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORUSERLOG_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELUSERLOG_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/users_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/users_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDUSERS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEUSERS_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTUSERS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORUSERS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELUSERS_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/web_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/web_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEB_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEB_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEB_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEB_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEB_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/webdav_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/webdav_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEBDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEBDAV_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEBDAV_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEBDAV_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEBDAV_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/webfinger_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/_includes/webfinger_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables Name Type Default Value Description OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEBFINGER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing. OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEBFINGER_TRACING_TYPE string The type of tracing. Defaults to &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;, which is the same as &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo;. Allowed tracing types are &amp;lsquo;jaeger&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; as of now. OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEBFINGER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string The endpoint of the tracing agent. OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEBFINGER_TRACING_COLLECTOR string The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. Only used if the tracing endpoint is unset. OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEBFINGER_LOG_LEVEL string The log level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/env-var-deltas/4.0.0-5.0.0-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/env-var-deltas/4.0.0-5.0.0-added/</guid>
      <description>Added Variables between oCIS 4.0.0 and oCIS 5.0.0 File Variable Description Default ocis-pkg/shared/shared_types.go OCIS_CACHE_DISABLE_PERSISTENCE Disables persistence of the cache. Only applies when store type &amp;rsquo;nats-js-kv&amp;rsquo; is configured. false ocis-pkg/registry/registry.go MICRO_REGISTRY (important change) The Go micro registry type to use. Supported types are: &amp;lsquo;memory&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;nats-js-kv&amp;rsquo; (default) and &amp;lsquo;kubernetes&amp;rsquo;. Note that &amp;rsquo;nats&amp;rsquo;, &amp;rsquo;etcd&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;consul&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;mdns&amp;rsquo; are deprecated and will be removed in a later version. Only change on supervision of ownCloud Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/env-var-deltas/4.0.0-5.0.0-removed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/env-var-deltas/4.0.0-5.0.0-removed/</guid>
      <description>Removed Variables between oCIS 4.0.0 and oCIS 5.0.0 File Variable Replacement Description services/auth-basic/pkg/config/config.go LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD OCIS_LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD Password to use for authenticating the &amp;lsquo;bind_dn&amp;rsquo;. services/graph/pkg/config/config.go LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD OCIS_LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD Password to use for authenticating the &amp;lsquo;bind_dn&amp;rsquo;. services/groups/pkg/config/config.go LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD OCIS_LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD Password to use for authenticating the &amp;lsquo;bind_dn&amp;rsquo;. services/idp/pkg/config/config.go LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD OCIS_LDAP_BIND_PASSWORD Password to use for authenticating the &amp;lsquo;bind_dn&amp;rsquo;. services/sharing/pkg/config/config.go SHARING_EVENTS_TLS_ROOT_CA_CERT SHARING_EVENTS_TLS_ROOT_CA_CERTIFICATE The root CA certificate used to validate the server&amp;rsquo;s TLS certificate. If provided SHARING_EVENTS_TLS_INSECURE will be seen as false.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
