<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Introduce an accounts service</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</guid>
      <description>Status: superseded by ADR-0003 Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm, @micbar, @pmaier1 Date: 2020-06-15  Technical Story: persist accounts
Context and Problem Statement     To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email und username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes. While there is an account porting protocol that describes how a relying party (RP) such as ownCloud should behave, it still requires the RP to maintain its own user identifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy as an app in ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/deployments/oc10-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/deployments/oc10-app/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Deploying ownCloud Web Configure oauth2 Configure ownCloud 10  Set ownCloud Web address Configure link routing Make ownCloud Web the default web interface   Configure ownCloud Web Integrate ownCloud Classic features in ownCloud Web  Add links to the app switcher Add links to the user menu ONLYOFFICE Collabora Online   Accessing ownCloud Web      The ownCloud Web is being deployed as an app to ownCloud marketplace to enable easy early integration into existing ownCloud 10 instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:03:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Framework Overview of the approach In-depth configuration Flows  Examples  Expected loading locations Only config files Using ENV variables   Workflows  Supervised Unsupervised     Shared Values  Log config keys   Default config values (in yaml)      Configuration Framework     In order to simplify deployments and development the configuration model from oCIS aims to be simple yet flexible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Components of the File picker  File picker Location picker        ownCloud File picker is a web component which can be integrated into existing web applications. It connects to an ownCloud server and enables a user to select resources which are then provided in a response of a fired event. Visit installation to see how to integrate the File picker into your product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Persist accounts in a CS3 storage</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm Date: 2020-08-21  Technical Story: File system based indexing
Context and Problem Statement     To set up High Availability (HA) or a geo-replicated setup we need to persist accounts in a distributed way. To efficiently query the accounts by email or username, and not only by id, they need to be indexed. Unfortunately, the bleve index we currently store locally on disk cannot be shared by multiple instances, preventing a scale out deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Use external User Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0003-external-user-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0003-external-user-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: superseded by 17. Allow read only external User Management Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2022-02-08  Technical Story: Skip account-service by talking to CS3 user-api
Context and Problem Statement     To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email and username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</guid>
      <description>Setup authentication  OpenID Connect config OAuth2 config Pass bearer token   Install File picker package Select browser storage Integrate in HTML page with vanilla JavaScript Integrate in Vue web application Set correct variation Theming Buttons and events  Select button Cancel button        Setup authentication     The config for the server backend and authentication needs to be provided in json format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Support Hot Migration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0004-support-hot-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 20:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0004-support-hot-migration/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-03-16  Technical Story: [description | ticket/issue URL]
Context and Problem Statement     Migration is one of the most important topics of the oCIS story. We need to provide a concept how to migrate from oC10 to oCIS.
Decision Drivers      Do not lose file blob or metadata.  To prevent a sync surge from clients the etag for files should be migrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Resources</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</guid>
      <description>Access resources      If using File picker as a web component, it is returning selected resources via events called select and update. To access them, you need to set an event listener where you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to get them as part of the response of the callback function.
Access resources     &amp;lt;file-picker id=&amp;#34;file-picker&amp;#34; variation=&amp;#34;resource&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/file-picker&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const item = document.getElementById(&amp;#39;file-picker&amp;#39;) let resources = [] item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Account Management through CS3 API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0005-cs3-api-account-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0005-cs3-api-account-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-04-12  Technical Story: Write only management API for User and Group resources
Context and Problem Statement     What would be a more effective way of using network resources and handle account management within the oCIS-Reva ecosystem? Separating account management at the service level is pragmatic and allows for fast iterations, but also steadily accumulates inconsistencies and bloats technical debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</guid>
      <description>Variation  File Picker Location Picker   Actions  Select Cancel        It is possible to customise certain parts of the File Picker with the help of props.
Variation     File picker comes in two different variations - File Picker and Location Picker. To specify which one should be used, set property variation to resource or location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. Service Discovery within oCIS and Reva</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0006-service-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0006-service-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-04-19  Technical Story: Introduce Named Services.
Context and Problem Statement     Reva relies heavily on config files. A known implication of this approach are having to know a-priori where a service is running (host + port). We want to move away from hardcoded values and rely instead on named services for service discovery. Furthermore, we would like both platforms (Reva + oCIS) to have the same source of truth at any given time, not having one to notify the other whenever a service status changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Provider</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesprovider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesprovider/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this.  Spaces Provider     A storage provider manages resources identified by a reference by accessing a storage system with a storage driver.
 Frontend     The oCIS frontend service starts all services that handle incoming HTTP requests:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Component reference</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</guid>
      <description>Props Events      &amp;lt;file-picker&amp;gt; Props        Property Type Default Description     variation String  Specifies if File Picker (resource) or Location Picker (location) should be used   configLocation String window.location.origin + &#39;/file-picker-config.json&#39; Defines where the config file should be located   bearerToken String null Bearer token used for requests authentication. If specified, authorization step is skipped   configObject `String Object`    isSdkProvided Boolean false Asserts whether ownCloud SDK is already initialised in the consuming app   selectBtnLabel String null Replaces the select button label   isSelectBtnDisplayed Boolean true Asserts whether the select button should be displayed   cancelBtnLabel String nulll Displays the cancel button and uses the given value as a label   isOdsProvided Boolean false Asserts whether the ownCloud Design System has been already initialised in the consuming app   locale String null Sets the language in which the File Picker should be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. Open Graph API for oCIS File Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0007-api-for-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0007-api-for-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-03-19  Technical Story: API to enable the concept of Spaces
Context and Problem Statement     As one of the building blocks for Spaces in oCIS we plan to add an API that returns information about available spaces. This ADR discusses the API design oriented on the Microsoft Graph API.
 Note: The term &amp;ldquo;spaces&amp;rdquo; is used here in the context of &amp;ldquo;a space where files can be saved&amp;rdquo;, similar to a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</guid>
      <description>Focusing content of File Picker Initial folder load focus      File Picker comes only with partial focus management. If you want to focus an element, it needs to be achieved through a code in the consuming app.
Focusing content of File Picker     If you&amp;rsquo;re including File Picker as a web component, managing focus is slightly different from focusing content of any other component in the DOM tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8. Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0008-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0008-configuration/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @pmaier1 Date: 2021-05-03  Context and Problem Statement     As per urfave/cli&amp;rsquo;s doc:
 The precedence for flag value sources is as follows (highest to lowest):
Command line flag value from user Environment variable (if specified) Configuration file (if specified) Default defined on the flag   An issue arises in point 2, in the sense that configuration file refers to a single file containing the value for the env variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9. Extension Template</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0009-extension-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0009-extension-template/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @c0rby  Date: 2021-06-10  Technical Story: [description | ticket/issue URL] Context and Problem Statement     We want to accelerate and simplify extension development by removing the necessity to type or copy the boilerplate code. Can we provide a template or a similar mechanism to aid when developing new extensions?
Decision Drivers      The solution should be easily maintainable.  It should always be up-to-date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Registry</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesregistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesregistry/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this.  Storage Space Registries     A storage spaces registry manages the namespace for a user: it is used by clients to look up storage spaces a user has access to, the /dav/spaces endpoint to access it via WabDAV, and where the client should mount it in the users personal namespace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Extension Policies</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0010-policy-enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0010-policy-enforcement/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2021-06-30  Context and Problem Statement     There should be a way to impose certain limitations in areas of the code that require licensing. This document researches an approach to achieve this goal, while limiting the scope to the enforcement side of it. The architecture for a policy system must be composed of 2 parts:
 License creation and validation Enforcement  It is desirable to keep both systems isolated, since the implementation of the latter has to be done within the constraints of the codebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Deployment</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/continuous_deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/continuous_deployment/</guid>
      <description>oCIS with Traefik  Latest Released   oCIS with WOPI server  Latest Released   oCIS with latest ownCloud Web  Latest   oCIS with Keycloak  Latest Released   Parallel deployment of oC10 and oCIS  Latest   oCIS with Hello extension  Latest   oCIS with S3 storage backend (MinIO)  Latest   oCIS with LDAP for users and groups  Latest Released      We are continuously deploying the following deployment examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring &amp; Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/monitoring-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/monitoring-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Overview about the proposed solution  Monitoring &amp;amp; tracing clients Monitoring &amp;amp; tracing server      Monitoring and tracing gives developers and admin insights into a complex system, in this case oCIS.
If you are a developer and want to trace during developing you should have a look at example server setup.
This documentation describes how to set up a long-running monitoring &amp;amp; tracing infrastructure for one or multiple oCIS servers or deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-registry/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-registry/apps/</guid>
      <description>oCIS is all about files. But most of the time you want to do something with files that is beyond the basic upload, download and share behavior. Therefore, oCIS has a concept for apps, that can handle specific file types, so called mime types.
App provider capability     The capabilities endpoint (e.g. https://localhost:9200/ocs/v1.php/cloud/capabilities?format=json) gives you following capabilities which are relevant for the app provider:
{ &amp;#34;ocs&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;data&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;capabilities&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;files&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;app_providers&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;enabled&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Source code   Configuration    Options   Sentry   Setting up backend and running Running      Installation     Docker     Make sure to have Docker, Docker-Compose, Node.js and Yarn installed.
This setup currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on Windows out of the box.
 Workaround One of our contributors has opened a PR to a dependency that prevents us from successfully bundling the frontend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. WebUI URL format</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0011-global-url-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0011-global-url-format/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @refs, @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @fschade, @tbsbdr, @kulmann Date: 2021-07-07  Context and Problem Statement     When speaking about URLs we have to make a difference between browser URLs and API URLs. Only browser URLs are visible to end users and will be bookmarked. The currently existing and bookmarked ownCloud 10 URLs look something like this:
GET https://demo.owncloud.com/apps/files/?dir=/path/to/resource&amp;amp;fileid=5472225 303 Location: https://demo.owncloud.com/apps/files/?dir=/path/to/resource When the URL contains a fileid parameter the server will look up the corresponding dir, overwriting whatever was set before the redirect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0012-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0012-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @mstingl, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2021-08-17  Context and Problem Statement     At the time of this writing we are in a situation where our logs have too much verbosity, rendering impossible or rather difficult to debug an instance. For this reason we are giving some care to our traces by updating dependencies from OpenCensus to OpenTelemetry.
Decision Drivers      We don&amp;rsquo;t want to rely only on logs to debug an instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage drivers</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/storagedrivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/storagedrivers/</guid>
      <description>A storage driver implements access to a storage system:
It maps the path and id based CS3 references to an appropriate storage system specific reference, e.g.:
 eos file ids posix inodes or paths deconstructed filesystem nodes  Storage providers     To manage the file tree oCIS uses storage providers that are accessing the underlying storage using a storage driver. The driver can be used to change the implementation of a storage aspect to better reflect the actual underlying storage capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Locking</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0013-locking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0013-locking/</guid>
      <description>Status: accepted Deciders: @hodyroff, @pmaier1, @jojowein, @dragotin, @micbar, @tbsbdr, @wkloucek Date: 2021-11-03  Context and Problem Statement     At the time of this writing no locking mechanisms exists in oCIS / REVA for both directories and files. The CS3org WOPI server implements a file based locking in order to lock files. This ADR discusses if this approach is ok for the general availability of oCIS or if changes are needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Microservices Runtime</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0014-microservices-runtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0014-microservices-runtime/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @mstingl, @pmaier1, @fschade Date: 2022-01-21  Context and Problem Statement     In an environment where shipping a single binary makes it easier for the end user to use oCIS, embedding a whole family of microservices within a package and running it leveraging the use of the Go language has plenty of value. In such environment, a runtime is necessary to orchestrate the services that run within it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. oCIS Event System</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0015-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:56:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0015-events/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @c0rby, @wkloucek Date: 2022-01-21  Context and Problem Statement     Overview     To be able to implement simple, flexible and independent inter service communication there is the idea to implement an event system in oCIS. A service can send out events which are received by one or more other services. The receiving service can cause different kinds of actions based on the event by utilizing the information that the event carries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Repository structure Starting points  Developing oCIS Developing extensions        Requirements     We want contribution to oCIS and the creation of extensions to be as easy as possible. So we are trying to reflect this in the tooling. It should be kept simple and quick to be set up.
Besides standard development tools like git and a text editor, you need the following software for development:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/namespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/namespaces/</guid>
      <description>A namespace is a set of paths with a common prefix. Depending on the endpoint you are talking to you will encounter a different kind of namespace: In ownCloud 10 all paths are considered relative to the users home. The CS3 API uses a global namespace and the storage providers use a local namespace with paths relative to the storage providers root.
 The different paths in the namespaces need to be translated while passing references from service to service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. Storage for Files Metadata</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0016-files-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0016-files-metadata/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @dragotin, @micbar, @C0rby Date: 2022-02-04  Context and Problem Statement     In addition to the file content we need to store metadata which is attached to a file. Metadata describes additional properties of a file. These properties need to be stored as close as possible to the file content to avoid inconsistencies. Metadata are key to workflows and search. We consider them as an additional value which enhances the file content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemd service</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/systemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/systemd/</guid>
      <description>Install the oCIS binary Systemd service definition Starting the oCIS service      Install the oCIS binary     Download the oCIS binary of your preferred version and for your CPU architecture and operating system from download.owncloud.com.
Rename the downloaded binary to ocis and move it to /usr/bin/. As a next step, you need to mark it as executable with chmod +x /usr/bin/ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Remote Setup</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/basic-remote-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/basic-remote-setup/</guid>
      <description>Start the oCIS fullstack server from binary  Using automatically generated certificates Using already present certificates   Start the oCIS fullstack server with Docker Compose      The default configuration of the oCIS binary and the owncloud/ocis docker image assume, that you access oCIS on localhost. This enables you to do quick testing and development without any configuration.
If you need to access oCIS running in a docker container, on a VM or a remote machine via another hostname than localhost, you need to configure this hostname in oCIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. Allow read only external User Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0017-allow-read-only-external-user-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0017-allow-read-only-external-user-management/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @rhafer Date: 2022-02-08  Context and Problem Statement     oCIS needs to be integrated with various external Authentication and Identity Management Systems. Usually oCIS will have no administrative access to such a system and we will not be allowed to reconfigure it to suit our needs (e.g. we will not be able to enhance the schema of an already existing LDAP Directory).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/users/</guid>
      <description>TODO add this to the storage overview? or is this a different part? That should be started as a separate service ? And documented elsewhere, e.g. in the accounts?
User and Group provisioning     In oc10 users are identified by a username, which cannot change, because it is used as a foreign key in several tables. For oCIS we are internally identifying users by a UUID, while using the username in the WebDAV and OCS APIs for backwards compatability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminology</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/terminology/</guid>
      <description>Communication is hard. And clear communication is even harder. You may encounter the following terms throughout the documentation, in the code or when talking to other developers. Just keep in mind that whenever you hear or read storage, that term needs to be clarified, because on its own it is too vague. PR welcome.
Logical concepts     Resources     A resource is the basic building block that oCIS manages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. File Search API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0018-file-search-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0018-file-search-api/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby Date: 2022-03-18  Context and Problem Statement     The ability to find files based on certain search terms is a key requirement for a system that provides the ability to store unstructured data on a large scale.
Decision Drivers      Have a simple yet powerful, scalable and performant way of finding files in oCIS Be able to construct intelligent searches based on metadata Allow the user to filter the search queries based on metadata  Considered Options      Libre Graph API WebDAV API  Decision Outcome     Chosen option: WebDAV API because the current WebUI is compatible with that API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Changes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/proposedchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/proposedchanges/</guid>
      <description>Some architectural changes still need to be clarified or changed. Maybe an ADR is in order for all of the below.
Reva Gateway changes     A dedicated shares storage provider     Currently, when a user accepts a share, a cs3 reference is created in the users /home/shares folder. This reference represents the mount point of a share and can be renamed, similar to the share jail in ownCloud 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. File Search Index</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0019-file-search-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0019-file-search-index/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby Date: 2022-03-18  Context and Problem Statement     The ability to find files based on certain search terms is a key requirement for a system that provides the ability to store unstructured data on a large scale.
More sophisticated search capabilities are expected and can be implemented, especially based on metadata.
To trigger the indexing of a file, the search service listens to create, update and delete events on the internal event bus of oCIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. File Search Query Language</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0020-file-search-query-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/adr/0020-file-search-query-language/</guid>
      <description>Status: proposed Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @C0rby Date: 2022-03-18  Context and Problem Statement     From the users perspective, the interface to search is just a single form field where the user enters one or more search terms. The minimum expectation is that the search returns file names and links to files that:
 have a file name that contains at least one of the search terms contain at least one of the search terms in the file contents have metadata that is equal or contains one of the search terms  Decision Drivers      The standard user should not be bothered by a query syntax The power user should also be able to narrow his search with an efficient and flexible syntax We need to consider different backend technologies which we need to access through an abstraction layer Using different indexing systems should lead to a slightly different feature set without changing the syntax completely  Considered Options      Simple Query Lucene Query Language Solr Query Language Elasticsearch Query Language  Decision Outcome     Chosen option: Simple Query, because it is a suitable MVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 12:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Command line flags   Root Command Sub Commands  hello server hello health        Configuration     Configuration using config files     Out of the box extensions will attempt to read configuration details from:
/etc/ocis $HOME/.ocis ./config For this configuration to be picked up, have a look at your extension root command and look for which default config name it has assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDAV with Basic Authentication</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-basic-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-basic-auth/</guid>
      <description>WebDAV with Basic Authentication     Basic Authentication is disabled by default in oCIS because of security considerations. In order to make the following Rclone commands work the oCIS administrator needs to enable Basic Authentication e.g. by setting the environment variable PROXY_ENABLE_BASIC_AUTH to true.
Please consider to use Rclone with OpenID Connect instead.
 For the usage of a WebDAV remote with Rclone see also the Rclone documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebDAV with OpenID Connect</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-oidc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/rclone/webdav-sync-oidc/</guid>
      <description>WebDAV with OpenID Connect     Rclone itself is not able to open and maintain an OpenID Connect session. But it is able to still use OpenID Connect for authentication by leveraging a so called OIDC-agent.
Setting up the OIDC-agent     You need to install the OIDC-agent from your OS&#39; package repository (e.g. Debian or MacOS).
Configuring the the OIDC-agent     Run the following command to add a OpenID Connect profile to your OIDC-agent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Commandline flags accounts server accounts health accounts wopiserver        Configuration     Configuration using config files     Out of the box extensions will attempt to read configuration details from:
/etc/ocis $HOME/.ocis ./config For this configuration to be picked up, have a look at your extension root command and look for which default config name it has assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/building/</guid>
      <description>Frontend Backend Documentation      As this project is built with Go and NodeJS, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go and NodeJS is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, NodeJS and Yarn, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.16. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/building/</guid>
      <description>Frontend Backend      As this project is built with Go and NodeJS, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go and NodeJS is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, NodeJS and Yarn, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.16. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building from source</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</guid>
      <description>Building ownCloud Web Updating dependencies Building the documentation  Setting up Viewing the documentation Deploying the documentation        Building ownCloud Web      Run yarn install to install dependencies Run yarn build to build Web and all apps included in the packages folder  Updating dependencies      Run yarn upgrade to update dependencies  Building the documentation     Setting up      Install hugo Run make docs  Viewing the documentation     To view the rendered docs in the browser run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-provider/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-provider/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38  # Autogenerated# Filename: app-provider-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9165token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9164protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142external_addr:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;driver:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;drivers:wopi:app_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;app_desktop_only:falseapp_icon_uri:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;app_internal_url:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;app_name:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;app_url:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;insecure:falsewopi_server_iop_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;wopi_server_external_url:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-registry/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/app-registry/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97  # Autogenerated# Filename: app-registry-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/audit/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/audit/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUDIT_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAUDIT_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORAUDIT_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEAUDIT_LOG_FILE string     AUDIT_DEBUG_ADDR string     AUDIT_DEBUG_TOKEN string     AUDIT_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    AUDIT_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    AUDIT_EVENTS_ENDPOINT string 127.0.0.1:9233 The address of the streaming service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-basic/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-basic/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69  # Autogenerated# Filename: auth-basic-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-bearer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-bearer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32  # Autogenerated# Filename: auth-bearer-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9149token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9148protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falseoidc:issuer:https://localhost:9200insecure:falseid_claim:preferred_usernameuid_claim:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;gid_claim:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-machine/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/auth-machine/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27  # Autogenerated# Filename: auth-machine-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9167token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9166protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falsemachine_auth_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/frontend/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/frontend/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59  # Autogenerated# Filename: frontend-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/gateway/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/gateway/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50  # Autogenerated# Filename: gateway-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9143token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9142protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falsecommit_share_to_storage_grant:truecommit_share_to_storage_ref:trueshare_folder_name:Sharesdisable_home_creation_on_login:truetransfer_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;transfer_expires:86400home_mapping:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;etag_cache_ttl:0frontend_public_url:https://localhost:9200users_endpoint:localhost:9144groups_endpoint:localhost:9160permissions_endpoint:localhost:9191sharing_endpoint:localhost:9150auth_basic_endpoint:localhost:9146auth_bearer_endpoint:localhost:9148auth_machine_endpoint:localhost:9166storage_public_link_endpoint:localhost:9178storage_users_endpoint:localhost:9157storage_shares_endpoint:localhost:9154app_registry_endpoint:localhost:9242storage_registry:driver:spacesrules:[]json:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGATEWAY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph-explorer/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph-explorer/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26  # Autogenerated# Filename: graph-explorer-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9136token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9135root:/graph-explorergraph_explorer:client_id:ocis-explorer.jsissuer:https://localhost:9200graph_url_base:https://localhost:9200graph_url_path:/graph   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_TYPE string  The sampler type: remote, const, probabilistic, ratelimiting (default remote).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57  # Autogenerated# Filename: graph-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9124token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9120root:/graphreva:address:127.0.0.1:9142token_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;spaces:webdav_base:https://localhost:9200webdav_path:/dav/spaces/default_quota:&amp;#34;1000000000&amp;#34;insecure:falseextended_space_properties_cache_ttl:0identity:backend:ldapldap:uri:ldaps://localhost:9235insecure:truebind_dn:uid=libregraph,ou=sysusers,o=libregraph-idmbind_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;use_server_uuid:falsewrite_enabled:trueuser_base_dn:ou=users,o=libregraph-idmuser_search_scope:subuser_filter:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;user_objectclass:inetOrgPersonuser_mail_attribute:mailuser_displayname_attribute:displayNameuser_name_attribute:uiduser_id_attribute:owncloudUUIDgroup_base_dn:ou=groups,o=libregraph-idmgroup_search_scope:subgroup_filter:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;group_objectclass:groupOfNamesgroup_name_attribute:cngroup_id_attribute:owncloudUUIDevents:endpoint:127.0.0.1:9233cluster:ocis-cluster   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGRAPH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGRAPH_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGRAPH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGRAPH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELGRAPH_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYGRAPH_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORGRAPH_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEGRAPH_LOG_FILE string     GRAPH_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/groups/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/groups/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67  # Autogenerated# Filename: groups-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idm/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idm/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30  # Autogenerated# Filename: idm-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falseidm:ldaps_addr:127.0.0.1:9235cert:~/.ocis/idm/ldap.crtkey:~/.ocis/idm/ldap.keydatabase:~/.ocis/idm/ocis.boltdbcreate_demo_users:falseservice_user_passwords:admin_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;idm_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;idp_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;admin_user_id:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDIDM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEIDM_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTIDM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORIDM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELIDM_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYIDM_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORIDM_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEIDM_LOG_FILE string     IDM_DEBUG_ADDR string     IDM_DEBUG_TOKEN string     IDM_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    IDM_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    IDM_LDAPS_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idp/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idp/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110 111 112 113 114 115 116 117 118  # Autogenerated# Filename: idp-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/nats/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/nats/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18  # Autogenerated# Filename: nats-config-example.yamllog:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsenats:host:127.0.0.1port:9233clusterid:ocis-clusterstore_dir:~/.ocis/nats   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELNATS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYNATS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORNATS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILENATS_LOG_FILE string     NATS_DEBUG_ADDR string     NATS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     NATS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    NATS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    NATS_NATS_HOST string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/notifications/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/notifications/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25  # Autogenerated# Filename: notifications-config-example.yamllog:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsenotifications:SMTP:smtp_host:127.0.0.1smtp_port:&amp;#34;1025&amp;#34;smtp_sender:noreply@example.comsmtp_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;events:endpoint:127.0.0.1:9233cluster:ocis-clustergroup:notificationsreva_gateway:127.0.0.1:9142machine_auth_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILENOTIFICATIONS_LOG_FILE string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_ADDR string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    NOTIFICATIONS_SMTP_HOST string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocdav/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocdav/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36  # Autogenerated# Filename: ocdav-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9163token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:0protocol:tcpprefix:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;token_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falsewebdav_namespace:/users/{{.Id.OpaqueId}}files_namespace:/users/{{.Id.OpaqueId}}shares_namespace:/Sharespublic_url:https://localhost:9200insecure:falsegateway_request_timeout:84300middleware:auth:credentials_by_user_agent:{}   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocs/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocs/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47  # Autogenerated# Filename: ocs-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9114token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9110root:/ocscors:allowed_origins:- &amp;#39;*&amp;#39;allowed_methods:- GET- POST- PUT- PATCH- DELETE- OPTIONSallowed_headers:- Authorization- Origin- Content-Type- Accept- X-Requested-Withallowed_credentials:truetoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/proxy/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/proxy/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 93 94 95 96 97 98 99 100 101 102 103 104 105 106 107 108 109 110  # Autogenerated# Filename: proxy-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/search/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/search/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28  # Autogenerated# Filename: search-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9224token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9220data_path:~/.ocis/searchreva:address:127.0.0.1:9142events:endpoint:127.0.0.1:9233cluster:ocis-clustergroup:searchmachine_auth_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSEARCH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPESEARCH_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSEARCH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSEARCH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSEARCH_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSEARCH_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORSEARCH_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILESEARCH_LOG_FILE string     SEARCH_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54  # Autogenerated# Filename: settings-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9194token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9190root:/cache_ttl:604800cors:allowed_origins:- &amp;#39;*&amp;#39;allowed_methods:- GET- POST- PUT- PATCH- DELETE- OPTIONSallowed_headers:- Authorization- Origin- Content-Type- Accept- X-Requested-Withallowed_credentials:truegrpc:addr:127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/sharing/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/sharing/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54  # Autogenerated# Filename: sharing-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9151token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9150protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142events:endpoint:127.0.0.1:9233cluster:ocis-clusterskip_user_groups_in_token:falseuser_sharing_driver:jsonuser_sharing_drivers:json:file:~/.ocis/storage/shares.jsoncs3:provider_addr:127.0.0.1:9215system_user_id:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;system_user_idp:internalsystem_user_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;owncloudsql:db_username:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;db_password:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;db_host:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;db_port:0db_name:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;user_storage_mount_id:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;public_sharing_driver:jsonpublic_sharing_drivers:json:file:~/.ocis/storage/publicshares.jsoncs3:provider_addr:127.0.0.1:9215system_user_id:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;system_user_idp:internalsystem_user_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSHARING_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-publiclink/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-publiclink/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28  # Autogenerated# Filename: storage-publiclink-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9179token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9178protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falsestorage_provider:mount_id:7993447f-687f-490d-875c-ac95e89a62a4   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-shares/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-shares/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29  # Autogenerated# Filename: storage-shares-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9156token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9154protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142skip_user_groups_in_token:falsemount_id:7639e57c-4433-4a12-8201-722fd0009154readonly:falseuser_share_provider_endpoint:localhost:9150   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-system/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-system/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38  # Autogenerated# Filename: storage-system-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9217token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9215protocol:tcphttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9216protocol:tcptoken_manager:jwt_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;reva:address:127.0.0.1:9142system_user_id:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;system_user_api_key:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;skip_user_groups_in_token:falsedriver:ocisdrivers:ocis:root:~/.ocis/storage/metadatadata_server_url:http://localhost:9216/datatemp_folder:~/.ocis/tmp/metadatadata_provider_insecure:false   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-users/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage-users/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71  # Autogenerated# Filename: storage-users-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/store/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/store/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21  # Autogenerated# Filename: store-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9464token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9460data_path:~/.ocis/store   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORE_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORE_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORE_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORE_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILESTORE_LOG_FILE string     STORE_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/thumbnails/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/thumbnails/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40  # Autogenerated# Filename: thumbnails-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9189token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsegrpc:addr:127.0.0.1:9185http:addr:127.0.0.1:9186root:/thumbnailsthumbnail:resolutions:- 16x16- 32x32- 64x64- 128x128- 1920x1080- 3840x2160- 7680x4320filesystem_storage:root_directory:~/.ocis/thumbnailswebdav_allow_insecure:falsecs3_allow_insecure:falsereva_gateway:127.0.0.1:9142font_map_file:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;transfer_secret:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;data_endpoint:http://127.0.0.1:9186/thumbnails/data   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/users/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/users/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67  # Autogenerated# Filename: users-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/web/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/web/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50  # Autogenerated# Filename: web-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9104token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9100root:/cache_ttl:604800asset:path:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;file:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;web:path:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;theme_server:https://localhost:9200theme_path:/themes/owncloud/theme.jsonconfig:server:https://localhost:9200theme:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;version:0.1.0oids:metadata_url:https://localhost:9200/.well-known/openid-configurationauthority:https://localhost:9200client_id:webresponse_type:codescope:openid profile emailapps:- files- search- preview- text-editor- pdf-viewer- external- user-managementexternal_apps:[]options:hideSearchBar:false   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEB_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEB_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEB_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEB_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEB_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYWEB_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORWEB_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEWEB_LOG_FILE string     WEB_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/webdav/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/webdav/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41  # Autogenerated# Filename: webdav-config-example.yamltracing:enabled:falsetype:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;endpoint:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;collector:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;log:level:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pretty:falsecolor:falsefile:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;debug:addr:127.0.0.1:9119token:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;pprof:falsezpages:falsehttp:addr:127.0.0.1:9115root:/cors:allowed_origins:- &amp;#39;*&amp;#39;allowed_methods:- GET- POST- PUT- PATCH- DELETE- OPTIONSallowed_headers:- Authorization- Origin- Content-Type- Accept- X-Requested-Withallow_credentials:trueocis_public_url:https://127.0.0.1:9200webdav_namespace:/users/{{.Id.OpaqueId}}reva_gateway:127.0.0.1:9142   Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEBDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Hints</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idm/configuration_hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idm/configuration_hints/</guid>
      <description>TLS Server Certificates     By default IDM generates a self-signed certificate and key on first startup to be able to provide TLS protected services. The certificate is stored in idm/ldap.crt inside the oCIS base data directory. The key is in idm/ldap.key in the same directory. You can use a custom server certificate by setting the IDM_LDAPS_CERT and IDM_LDAPS_KEY.
Default / Demo Users     On startup IDM creates a set of default services users that are needed internally to provide access to IDM to other oCIS services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/spaces/</guid>
      <description>Graph Service Spaces API  Methods   Examples  Starting conditions        Graph Service     The Graph service is a reference implementation of the MS Graph API. There are no libraries doing any work only a set of routes and handlers.
Spaces API     The Spaces API makes use of the MS Graph API Drive resource to represent the concept of a Storage Space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theming</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idp/theming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/idp/theming/</guid>
      <description>Intro Customizing assets  Static assets CSS Containers  What pages to theme   Components Images Locales   Building assets      Intro     Our default IDP UI is built with the LibreGraph Connect React app. Even though this app comes already with a simple theming options, we have compiled our own edited version of the app with more advanced changes than the default theming offers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS as individual services</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_individual_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_individual_services/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup      Overview      oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup oCIS running as individual services (each extension in its own containers)  Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists of at least 24 containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Hello extension</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_hello/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup      Overview      oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy oCIS Hello extension runs beside the main oCIS stack and providing the Hello functionality Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup  Find this example on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Keycloak</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_keycloak/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup      Overview      oCIS and Keycloak running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Keycloak acting as the IDP for oCIS Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup  Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists 4 containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with LDAP</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_ldap/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install this example   Local setup      Overview      Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup OpenLDAP server with demo users LDAP admin interface to edit users oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy  oCIS is using the LDAP server as user backend    Find this example on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with S3 storage backend (MinIO)</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_s3/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup      Overview      oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy MinIO as S3 compatible storage provider oCIS is configured to use S3 as user storage provider Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup  Find this example on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with Traefik</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_traefik/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup      Overview      oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup  Find this example on GitHub
The docker stack consists of two containers. One of them is Traefik, a proxy which is terminating ssl and forwards the requests to oCIS in the internal docker network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oCIS with WOPI server</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_wopi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/ocis_wopi/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install oCIS and Traefik   Local setup Local setup for web development      Overview      oCIS, Wopi server, Collabora and OnlyOffice running behind Traefik as reverse proxy Collabora and OnlyOffice enable you to edit documents in your browser Wopi server acts as a bridge to make the oCIS storage accessible to Collabora and OnlyOffice Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup  Find this example on GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel deployment of oC10 and oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/oc10_ocis_parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/oc10_ocis_parallel/</guid>
      <description>Overview Server Deployment  Requirements Install this example   Local setup      Overview      This setup reflects stage 6 of the oC10 to oCIS migration plan Traefik generating self-signed certificates for local setup or obtaining valid SSL certificates for a server setup OpenLDAP server with demo users LDAP admin interface to edit users Keycloak as OpenID Connect provider in federation with the LDAP server ownCloud 10 with MariaDB and Redis  ownCloud 10 is configured to synchronize users from the LDAP server ownCloud 10 is used to use OpenID Connect for authentication with Keycloak   oCIS running behind Traefik as reverse proxy  oCIS is using the ownCloudSQL storage driver on the same files and same database as ownCloud 10 oCIS is using Keycloak as OpenID Connect provider oCIS is using the LDAP server as user backend   All requests to both oCIS and oC10 are routed through the oCIS proxy and will be routed based on an OIDC claim to one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>What is Kubernetes  References and further reads How does oCIS fit in the Kubernetes model   What is Minikube What is kubectl What are Helm Charts, and why they are useful for oCIS  Installing Helm   Setting up Minikube  Start minikube   Run a chart  Requirements Setup   Setting up an external identity provider What is GCP  Can Helm charts run on GCP?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing ownCloud Web  Versioning Release Guide Next steps        Releasing ownCloud Web     OwnCloud Web can be hosted standalone, as ownCloud 10 app or as part of oCIS.
Versioning     We follow the Semantic Versioning scheme. Therefore, each change is of one of the possible types: Bugfix, Change, Enhancement, Security.
The highest type before a new release determines the version update number, so if it&amp;rsquo;s only Bugfix and Security changes the next release will be a PATCH version bump, if there&amp;rsquo;s at least one Enhancement within the changes this leads to a MINOR version bump, while Change type changes make for a new MAJOR release version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services Communication</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/services-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/services-communication/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cephfs</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</guid>
      <description>Development Architecture Implemented Aspects Future work      oCIS intends to make the aspects of existing storage systems available as transparently as possible, but the static sync algorithm of the desktop client relies on some form of recursive change time propagation on the server side to detect changes. While this can be bolted on top of existing file systems with inotify, the kernel audit or a fuse based overlay filesystem, a storage system that already implements this aspect is preferable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decomposed FS on NFS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</guid>
      <description>NFS Server Setup NFS Client Mount oCIS Start using the NFS Share      oCIS&#39; default storage backend is the Decomposed FS. The Decomposed FS can be set up to run on a NFS share. That way the same storage can be provided over network to other nodes running oCIS.
This document summarizes a few important considerations of the NFS setup and describes a tested setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Stat Polling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/efficient-stat-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/architecture/efficient-stat-polling/</guid>
      <description>The fallback sync mechanism uses the ETag to determine which part of a sync tree needs to be checked by recursively descending into folders whose ETag has changed. The ETag can be calculated using a stat() call in the filesystem and we are going to explore how many stat() calls are necessary and how the number might be reduced.
ETag propagation     What does ETag propagation mean? Whenever a file changes its content or metadata the ETag or &amp;ldquo;entity tag&amp;rdquo; changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridge</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/bridge/</guid>
      <description>Current status How to do it  Install the owncloud 10 graphapi app Enable the graphapi app Grab ocis! Start ocis glauth  configure it Run it! Check it is up and running   Start ocis storage-gateway, storage-authbasic and storage-userprovider Start ocis storage-userprovider Start ocis idp  Set environment variables   Configure clients  Run it! Check it is up and running   Start ocis proxy Start ocis-web  Run it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build/</guid>
      <description>Build requirements Get the sources Build the oCIS binary Build a local oCIS docker image      Build requirements     see Development - Getting Started
Get the sources     git clone https://github.com/owncloud/ocis.git cd ocis Build the oCIS binary     You only need to run following command if you have changed protobuf definitions or the frontend part in one of the extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</guid>
      <description>Docker dev environment for eos storage  1. Start eos &amp;amp; ocis containers 2. LDAP support 3. Home storage 4. Users storage 5. Metadata storage 6. Accounts service   Verification Further exploration Cleaning up Troubleshooting  Docker-compose exits right away Where are the logs ? How do I update a service in the ocis container? Creation and upload of files does not work Uploading big files appears to hang Running out of space quickly        oCIS can be configured to run on top of eos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/users/</guid>
      <description>Users API  Reading users  GET /me GET /users GET /users/{userid or accountname}   Creating / Updating Users  POST /users  Request Body Response   DELETE /users/{id} PATCH /users/{id}   Change password  POST /me/changePassword  Request Body            Users API     The Users API is implementing a subset of the functionality of the MS Graph User resource The JSON representation of a User handled by the Users API looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beta testplan</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/beta-testplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/beta-testplan/</guid>
      <description>Beta Testing     This document is supposed to give you some ideas how and what to test on ocis. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to be an extensive list of all tests to be done, rather it should help you, as beta-tester, to get started and enable you to get creative and create your own test-cases. Derive from these examples, be creative, do unusual and unconventional things, to try to break things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/testing/</guid>
      <description>Testing with test suite in docker  Run full test suite Run single feature test oCIS image to be tested (or: skip build and take existing image) Test log output Cleanup   Testing with test suite natively installed  Getting the tests Run ocis Run the acceptance tests use existing tests for BDD   Running tests for parallel deployment  Setup the parallel deployment environment Getting the test helpers Run the acceptance tests        To run tests in the test suite you have two options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spaces/</guid>
      <description>Editing a Storage Space  Updating a space property Updating a space description Quotas  Quota Enforcement  Considerations       Storage Spaces Shares Notes      Editing a Storage Space     The OData specification allows for a mirage of ways of addressing an entity. We will support addressing a Drive entity by its unique identifier, which is the one the graph-api returns when listing spaces, and its format is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Registry Discovery</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction     In order for an oCIS client to access oCIS storage spaces for an End-User, the client needs to know where the oCIS instance is. oCIS uses WebFinger RFC7033 to locate the oCIS instance for an End-User.
This discovery is optional. If the client has another way of discovering the OpenID instance, e.g. when logging in with a username a static domain might be configured or the domain in the URL might be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Setting up the ownCloud Server  Adjusting config.php Setting up OAuth2 Setting up Web   Running Web Running acceptance tests      Prerequisites     Decide on which host and port Web will be served, for example https://web-host:9100/web-path/. In this document, we will refer to the following:
 &amp;lt;web-url&amp;gt; as the full URL, for example https://web-host:9100/web-path/ &amp;lt;web-domain&amp;gt; as the protocol, domain and port, for example: https://web-host:9100  Setting up the ownCloud Server     Make sure you have an ownCloud Server already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/extensions/</guid>
      <description>oCIS is all about files, sync and share - but most of the time there is more you want to do with your files, e.g. having a different view on your photo collection or editing your offices files in an online file editor. ownCloud 10 faced the same problem and solved it with applications, which can extend the functionality of ownCloud 10 in a wide range. Since oCIS is different in its architecture compared to ownCloud 10, we had to come up with a similar (yet slightly different) solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/graph/groups/</guid>
      <description>Groups API  Reading groups  GET /groups GET /groups/{groupid}   Getting Group Members  GET /groups/{groupid}/members   Creating / Updating Groups  POST /groups  Request Body Response   DELETE /groups/{id} PATCH /groups/{id}   Adding a single member to a group  POST /groups/{id}/members/$ref   Adding multiple members in a single request  PATCH /groups/{id}   Removing a member  DELETE /groups/{groupid}/members/{id}/$ref          Groups API     The Groups API is implementing a subset of the functionality of the MS Graph Group resource The JSON representation of a Group as handled by the Groups API looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/web/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/web/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing  Package Hierarchy  Prerequisites Updating ocis-web          Releasing     The next generation Web Frontend is shipped as an oCIS Extension. The ocis-web extension is also embedded in the single binary and part of the ocis server command.
To update this package within all the deliveries, we need to update the package in the following chain from the bottom to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 16:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</guid>
      <description>The migration happens in subsequent stages while the service is online. First all users need to migrate to the new architecture, then the global namespace needs to be introduced. Finally, the data on disk can be migrated user by user by switching the storage driver.
@jfd: It might be easier to introduce the spaces api in oc10 and then migrate to oCIS. We cannot migrate both at the same time, the architecture to oCIS (which will change fileids) and introduce a global namespace (which requires stable fileids to let clients handle moves without redownloading).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ports</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/ports/</guid>
      <description>Currently, every service needs to be configured with a port so oCIS can start them on localhost. We will automate this by using a service registry for more services, until eventually only the proxy has to be configured with a public port.
For now, the storage service uses these ports to preconfigure those services:
   port service     9109 health, used by cli?   9140 frontend   9141 frontend debug   9142 gateway   9143 gateway debug   9144 users   9145 users debug   9146 authbasic   9147 authbasic debug   9148 authbearer   9149 authbearer debug   9150 sharing   9151 sharing debug   9154 storage home grpc   9155 storage home http   9156 storage home debug   9157 storage users grpc   9158 storage users http   9159 storage users debug   9160 groups   9161 groups debug   9164 storage app-provider   9165 storage app-provider debug   9178 storage public link   9179 storage public link data   9215 storage meta grpc   9216 storage meta http   9217 storage meta debug    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Login Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</guid>
      <description>Login Flow     The following sequence diagram describes the openid connect auth code flow. The eight numbered steps and notes correspond to the openid connect auth code flow steps. Example requests are based on the spec as well:
 sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ %% this documents the login workflow %% examples taken from the oidc spec https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#CodeFlowAuth %% TODO add PKCE, see https://developer.okta.com/blog/2019/08/22/okta-authjs-pkce#use-pkce-to-make-your-apps-more-secure participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant glauth as ocis-glauth participant graph as ocis-graph participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as external LDAP server user-+client: What is the content of my home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</guid>
      <description>Metrics     This service provides some Prometheus metrics through the debug endpoint, you can optionally secure the metrics endpoint by some random token, which has to be configured either through the flag --debug-token or the environment variable OCIS_DEBUG_TOKEN mentioned above. By default, the metrics endpoint is bound to http://0.0.0.0:8001/metrics.
 go_gc_duration_seconds A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_sum A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_count A summary of the GC invocation durations go_goroutines Number of goroutines that currently exist go_info Information about the Go environment go_memstats_alloc_bytes Number of bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_alloc_bytes_total Total number of bytes allocated, even if freed go_memstats_buck_hash_sys_bytes Number of bytes used by the profiling bucket hash table go_memstats_frees_total Total number of frees go_memstats_gc_cpu_fraction The fraction of this program&amp;rsquo;s available CPU time used by the GC since the program started go_memstats_gc_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for garbage collection system metadata go_memstats_heap_alloc_bytes Number of heap bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_heap_idle_bytes Number of heap bytes waiting to be used go_memstats_heap_inuse_bytes Number of heap bytes that are in use go_memstats_heap_objects Number of allocated objects go_memstats_heap_released_bytes Number of heap bytes released to OS go_memstats_heap_sys_bytes Number of heap bytes obtained from system go_memstats_last_gc_time_seconds Number of seconds since 1970 of last garbage collection go_memstats_lookups_total Total number of pointer lookups go_memstats_mallocs_total Total number of mallocs go_memstats_mcache_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mcache structures go_memstats_mcache_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mcache structures obtained from system go_memstats_mspan_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mspan structures go_memstats_mspan_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mspan structures obtained from system go_memstats_next_gc_bytes Number of heap bytes when next garbage collection will take place go_memstats_other_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for other system allocations go_memstats_stack_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by the stack allocator go_memstats_stack_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system for stack allocator go_memstats_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system go_threads Number of OS threads created promhttp_metric_handler_requests_in_flight Current number of scrapes being served promhttp_metric_handler_requests_total Total number of scrapes by HTTP status code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</guid>
      <description>Request Flow     The following sequence diagram describes the general request flow. It shows where account provisioning and token minting are happening:
 sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as corporate LDAP server user-+client: What is the content of my home? client-+proxy: PROPFIND Bearer auth using oidc auth token Note over client,proxy: What is in a bearer token?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public upload Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</guid>
      <description>Public Upload flow     The following diagram describes the flow of requests:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto  Entity Match Reference ResourceID   Scalar Value Types      ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto     Entity        Field Type Label Description     ref Reference     id ResourceID     name string     etag string     size uint64     last_modified_time google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto  Bool Bundle Identifier Int ListOption ListOptionValue ListValue MultiChoiceList Permission Resource Setting SingleChoiceList String UserRoleAssignment Value ValueWithIdentifier Bundle.Type Permission.Constraint Permission.Operation Resource.Type   Scalar Value Types      ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto     Bool        Field Type Label Description     default bool     label string      Bundle        Field Type Label Description     id string     name string     type Bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto  DeleteOptions Field ListOptions ReadOptions ReadOptions.WhereEntry Record Record.MetadataEntry WriteOptions   Scalar Value Types      ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto     DeleteOptions        Field Type Label Description     database string     table string      Field        Field Type Label Description     type string  type of value e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto  CS3Source WebdavSource ThumbnailType   Scalar Value Types      ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto     CS3Source        Field Type Label Description     path string     authorization string      WebdavSource        Field Type Label Description     url string  REQUIRED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto  IndexSpaceRequest IndexSpaceResponse SearchIndexRequest SearchIndexResponse SearchRequest SearchResponse IndexProvider SearchProvider   Scalar Value Types      ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto     IndexSpaceRequest        Field Type Label Description     space_id string     user_id string      IndexSpaceResponse     SearchIndexRequest        Field Type Label Description     page_size int32  Optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto  AddSettingToBundleRequest AddSettingToBundleResponse AssignRoleToUserRequest AssignRoleToUserResponse GetBundleRequest GetBundleResponse GetPermissionByIDRequest GetPermissionByIDResponse GetValueByUniqueIdentifiersRequest GetValueRequest GetValueResponse ListBundlesRequest ListBundlesResponse ListPermissionsByResourceRequest ListPermissionsByResourceResponse ListRoleAssignmentsRequest ListRoleAssignmentsResponse ListValuesRequest ListValuesResponse RemoveRoleFromUserRequest RemoveSettingFromBundleRequest SaveBundleRequest   requests and responses for settings bundles  SaveBundleResponse SaveValueRequest SaveValueResponse BundleService PermissionService RoleService ValueService   Scalar Value Types      ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto     AddSettingToBundleRequest        Field Type Label Description     bundle_id string     setting ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto  DatabasesRequest DatabasesResponse DeleteRequest DeleteResponse ListRequest ListResponse ReadRequest ReadResponse TablesRequest TablesResponse WriteRequest WriteResponse Store   Scalar Value Types      ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto     DatabasesRequest     DatabasesResponse        Field Type Label Description     databases string repeated     DeleteRequest        Field Type Label Description     key string     options ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 04:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto  GetThumbnailRequest GetThumbnailResponse ThumbnailService   Scalar Value Types      ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto     GetThumbnailRequest     A request to retrieve a thumbnail
   Field Type Label Description     filepath string  The path to the source image   thumbnail_type ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.ThumbnailType  The type to which the thumbnail should get encoded to.   width int32  The width of the thumbnail   height int32  The height of the thumbnail   webdav_source ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to ownCloud web  Linting and tests Changelog items   Code Conventions  Early returns Translations TypeScript Dependencies        This is a collection of tips and conventions to follow when working on the ownCloud web frontend. It is a living document, please open a PR if you find something missing.
Contributing to ownCloud web     Everyone is invited to contribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Bundles</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/bundles/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Bundle is a collection of settings, uniquely identified by the key of the extension registering the bundle and the key of the bundle itself. It&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to let oCIS extensions define settings and make them available to users. They are dynamically rendered into forms, available in the frontend.
As of now we support five different types of settings:
 boolean integer string single choice list of integers or strings multiple choice list of integers or strings  Each Setting is uniquely identified by a key within the bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Web Running Web Setting up oCIS Start oCIS Running tests      Setting up Web      Clone the repository Initally install all dependencies by running yarn install Copy ./config/config.json.sample-ocis to ./config/config.json and adjust values if required  Running Web      Start bundling web with a watcher by running yarn build:w  Setting up oCIS      Setup oCIS by following the setup instructions Start oCIS with local links to your bundled web frontend and config by running WEB_ASSET_PATH=.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/debugging/</guid>
      <description>Debugging  Start ocis  Use the debug binary and attach to the process as needed Start all services independently to replace one of them with a debug process   Gather error messages Managing dependencies and testing changes        Debugging     As a single binary for easy deployment running ocis server just forks itself to start all the services, which makes debugging those processes a little harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRPC API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/grpc/</guid>
      <description>hello.proto  GreetRequest GreetResponse Hello   Scalar Value Types      hello.proto     GreetRequest        Field Type Label Description     name string      GreetResponse        Field Type Label Description     message string      Hello        Method Name Request Type Response Type Description     Greet GreetRequest GreetResponse     Scalar Value Types        .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/running/</guid>
      <description>In order to use the Hello extension we need to configure and start oCIS first. After that we can run the Hello extension itself.
Configure and start oCIS     You can either start oCIS from a binary or build it from source.
No matter which way you choose, we need to create a configuration file for ownCloud Web, so that the Hello extension will be loaded in the frontend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/configuration-with-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_wopiserver/configuration-with-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Running ocis     In order to run this extension we will need to run oCIS first. For that clone and build the oCIS single binary from the github repo https://github.com/owncloud/ocis. After that we will need to create a config file for phoenix so that we can load the WOPI app in the frontend. Create a file web-config.json with the following contents.
{ &amp;#34;server&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;https://localhost:9200&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;theme&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;owncloud&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/settings/</guid>
      <description>oCIS provides an settings extension that other extensions can use to make settings accessible to users.
In case of the Hello extension administrator users are able to change the greeter message.
Settings are stored and presented to the user by the oCIS settings extension. It also exposes endpoints for registering and manipulating so called settings bundles.
The settings defined through settings bundles can be changed by authenticated users in ownCloud Web, if they have enough permissions to edit them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/ocis_hello/testing/</guid>
      <description>This repository provides a general guideline for creating tests for an oCIS extension. The tests can be written in various levels from unit, integration, and end-to-end. It is not essential to write tests on all these levels as it can be redundant in some cases. This repository provides a reference for all levels of tests.
Unit tests     Unit tests generally live inside *_test.go files in the /pkg directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Values</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/values/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Value is the value an authenticated user has chosen for a specific setting, defined in a settings bundle. For choosing settings values as a user the sole entry point is the ocis-web extension provided by this service.
Identifying settings values     A settings value is uniquely identified by four attributes. Three of them are coming from the definition of the setting within it&amp;rsquo;s settings bundle (see Settings Bundles for an example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 12:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/tracing/</guid>
      <description>By default, we use Jaeger for request tracing within oCIS. You can follow these steps to get started:
 Start Jaeger by using the all-in-one docker image: docker run -d --name jaeger \ -e COLLECTOR_ZIPKIN_HTTP_PORT=9411 \ -p 5775:5775/udp \ -p 6831:6831/udp \ -p 6832:6832/udp \ -p 5778:5778 \ -p 16686:16686 \ -p 14268:14268 \ -p 14250:14250 \ -p 9411:9411 \ jaegertracing/all-in-one:1.17  Every single oCIS service has its own environment variables for enabling and configuring tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/profiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 12:32:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/profiling/</guid>
      <description>0. Prerequisites  1. Clone Reva 2. Patch reva with the area that you want sampled. 3. Replace reva in oCIS go.mod with local version and build a new binary 4. Build a new ocis binary 5. Start oCIS server 6. Run pprof  Install pprof Collecting samples   Room for improvement References      0. Prerequisites      Go development kit of a supported version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running acceptance tests</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/testing/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Unit Tests  Unit test file structure   E2E Tests (Playwright)  Prerequisites Prepare &amp;amp; start web Start Docker Run E2E tests Options   Acceptance Tests (Nightwatch)  Prerequisites Prepare &amp;amp; start web Start Docker Run acceptance tests Watch the test run Watch the test report          Introduction     In order to allow us to make changes quickly, often and with a high level of confidence, we heavily rely on tests within the web repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running acceptance tests - all options</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/acceptance-tests-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/testing/acceptance-tests-all/</guid>
      <description>Setup backend  ownCloud 10 oCIS   Setup the ownCloud test Middleware Setup Selenium  Setup using Docker Setup using Docker Desktop for Mac Setup using standalone Selenium server   Setup ownCloud Web Run tests  with oC10 backend with oCIS backend Visual Regression Testing  Running the visual regression tests Updating the snapshots     Available settings to be set by environment variables Tips  too many open files   Acceptance Tests in CI  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Releasing  Package Hierarchy        Requirements     You need a working installation of the Go programming language, the Node runtime and the Yarn package manager installed to build the assets for a working release.
Releasing     The settings service doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a dedicated release process. Simply commit your changes, make sure linting and unit tests pass locally and open a pull request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/glossary/</guid>
      <description>In the context of this extension and oCIS in general, we are using the following terminology.
Configuration      System configuration e.g. service host names and ports Changes need to be propagated to other services Typically modified on the CLI  Settings      Application level settings e.g. default language Can be modified at runtime without restarting the service Typically modified in the UI  Preferences      User settings Subset of &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/tests/</guid>
      <description>Requirements Acceptance Tests  In the web repo  Optional: Build web to test local changes Dockerized acceptance test services   In the oCIS repo  Optional: Build settings UI to test local changes Start oCIS from binary Run settings acceptance tests          Requirements     You need a working installation of the Go programming language, the Node runtime and the Yarn package manager installed to run the acceptance tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 08:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/build-docs/</guid>
      <description>Build the documentation Add changes to the documentation      Build the documentation     For building the documentation you need to have Make and Go 1.14 or higher installed.  Just run make -C docs docs-serve from within the root level of the oCIS git repository. This will make documentation available on localhost:1313 and also do a hot reload if you change something in the (non autogenerated) documentation files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a server</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/preparing_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/deployment/preparing_server/</guid>
      <description>Example for Hetzner Cloud      Example for Hetzner Cloud       create server on Hetzner Cloud. Set labels &amp;ldquo;owner&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;for&amp;rdquo;. Example for hcloud cli: hcloud server create --type cx21 --image ubuntu-20.04 --ssh-key admin --name ocis-server --label owner=admin --label for=testing
  Configure DNS A-records for needed domains pointing on the servers ip address, for example in CloudFlare</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/continuous-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/development/continuous-integration/</guid>
      <description>Concepts Things done in CI Flags in commit message and PR title  Knowledge base        oCIS uses DRONE as CI system. You can find the pipeline logs here or in your PR.
Concepts     The pipeline is defined in Starlark and transformed to YAML upon pipeline run. This enables us to do a highly dynamic and non repeating pipeline configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</guid>
      <description>This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</guid>
      <description>The Infinite Scale Release Notes have been moved and are published with the ownCloud Documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</guid>
      <description>You may have asked yourself why there are major version 1 tags in our GitHub repository but the Readme still states ownCloud Infinite Scale is currently in a technical preview state. It will be subject to a lot of changes and is not yet ready for general production deployments.. How can that be if it&amp;rsquo;s a major version 1?
Our initial and also our current plan is to stick to SemVer as versioning scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/getting-started/demo-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/getting-started/demo-users/</guid>
      <description>oCIS has the option to create demo users during the first startup. These enable you to do quick testing and developing.
To create the demo users, run the initial setup step with an additional environment variable. IDM_CREATE_DEMO_USERS=true ./bin/ocis server will generate the demo users listed in the table below. By default, it only generates the admin and one user for IDP and Reva respectively.  Following users are available in the demo set:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Ranges</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/port-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/port-ranges/</guid>
      <description>oCIS extensions often need a port to expose their services to other services or the outside world. As users may have many different extensions running on the same machine, we should track port usage in the oCIS ecosystem. In the best case we ensure that each extension uses a non colliding port range, to make life of users easier.
This page tracks the knowingly used port ranges.
Feel free to &amp;ldquo;reserve&amp;rdquo; a free port range when you&amp;rsquo;re developing an extension by adding your extension to the list (see the edit button in the top right corner).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/app-provider_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/app-provider_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAPP_PROVIDER_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAPP_PROVIDER_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAPP_PROVIDER_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORAPP_PROVIDER_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/app-registry_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/app-registry_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAPP_REGISTRY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAPP_REGISTRY_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAPP_REGISTRY_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORAPP_REGISTRY_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/audit_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/audit_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUDIT_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAUDIT_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORAUDIT_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEAUDIT_LOG_FILE string     AUDIT_DEBUG_ADDR string     AUDIT_DEBUG_TOKEN string     AUDIT_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    AUDIT_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    AUDIT_EVENTS_ENDPOINT string 127.0.0.1:9233 The address of the streaming service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-basic_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-basic_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_TYPE string  The sampler type: remote, const, probabilistic, ratelimiting (default remote). See also https://www.jaegertracing.io/docs/latest/sampling/.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_BASIC_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. If specified, the tracing endpoint is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-bearer_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-bearer_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_BEARER_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_BEARER_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAUTH_BEARER_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORAUTH_BEARER_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-machine_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/auth-machine_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORAUTH_MACHINE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELAUTH_MACHINE_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYAUTH_MACHINE_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORAUTH_MACHINE_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/frontend_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/frontend_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDFRONTEND_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEFRONTEND_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTFRONTEND_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORFRONTEND_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELFRONTEND_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYFRONTEND_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORFRONTEND_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/gateway_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/gateway_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGATEWAY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGATEWAY_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGATEWAY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGATEWAY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELGATEWAY_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYGATEWAY_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORGATEWAY_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/graph-explorer_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/graph-explorer_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_TYPE string  The sampler type: remote, const, probabilistic, ratelimiting (default remote). See also https://www.jaegertracing.io/docs/latest/sampling/.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint of the tracing service.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGRAPH_EXPLORER_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. If specified, the tracing endpoint is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/graph_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/graph_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGRAPH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGRAPH_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGRAPH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGRAPH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELGRAPH_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYGRAPH_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORGRAPH_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEGRAPH_LOG_FILE string     GRAPH_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9124    GRAPH_DEBUG_TOKEN string     GRAPH_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    GRAPH_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    GRAPH_HTTP_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/groups_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/groups_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDGROUPS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEGROUPS_TRACING_TYPE string  The sampler type: remote, const, probabilistic, ratelimiting (default remote). See also https://www.jaegertracing.io/docs/latest/sampling/.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTGROUPS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORGROUPS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. If specified, the tracing endpoint is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/idm_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/idm_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDIDM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEIDM_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTIDM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORIDM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELIDM_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYIDM_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORIDM_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEIDM_LOG_FILE string     IDM_DEBUG_ADDR string     IDM_DEBUG_TOKEN string     IDM_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    IDM_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    IDM_LDAPS_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/idp_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/idp_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     IDP_PASSWORD_RESET_URI string  The URI where a user can reset their password.   OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDIDP_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEIDP_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTIDP_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORIDP_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELIDP_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYIDP_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORIDP_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEIDP_LOG_FILE string     IDP_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/nats_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/nats_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELNATS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYNATS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORNATS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILENATS_LOG_FILE string     NATS_DEBUG_ADDR string     NATS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     NATS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    NATS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    NATS_NATS_HOST string 127.0.0.1    NATS_NATS_PORT int 9233    NATS_NATS_CLUSTER_ID string ocis-cluster    NATS_NATS_STORE_DIR string ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/notifications_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/notifications_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_LOG_LEVELNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORNOTIFICATIONS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILENOTIFICATIONS_LOG_FILE string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_ADDR string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    NOTIFICATIONS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    NOTIFICATIONS_SMTP_HOST string 127.0.0.1    NOTIFICATIONS_SMTP_PORT string 1025    NOTIFICATIONS_SMTP_SENDER string noreply@example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/ocdav_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/ocdav_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEOCDAV_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTOCDAV_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOROCDAV_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELOCDAV_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYOCDAV_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLOROCDAV_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/ocs_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/ocs_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDOCS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEOCS_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTOCS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTOROCS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELOCS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYOCS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLOROCS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEOCS_LOG_FILE string     OCS_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9114    OCS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     OCS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    OCS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    OCS_HTTP_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/proxy_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/proxy_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDPROXY_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEPROXY_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTPROXY_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORPROXY_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELPROXY_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYPROXY_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORPROXY_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEPROXY_LOG_FILE string     PROXY_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9205    PROXY_DEBUG_TOKEN string     PROXY_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    PROXY_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    PROXY_HTTP_ADDR string 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/search_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/search_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSEARCH_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPESEARCH_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSEARCH_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSEARCH_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSEARCH_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSEARCH_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORSEARCH_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILESEARCH_LOG_FILE string     SEARCH_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9224    SEARCH_DEBUG_TOKEN string     SEARCH_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    SEARCH_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    SEARCH_GRPC_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/settings_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/settings_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSETTINGS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPESETTINGS_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSETTINGS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSETTINGS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSETTINGS_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSETTINGS_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORSETTINGS_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILESETTINGS_LOG_FILE string     SETTINGS_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9194    SETTINGS_DEBUG_TOKEN string     SETTINGS_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    SETTINGS_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    SETTINGS_HTTP_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/sharing_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/sharing_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSHARING_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESHARING_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSHARING_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSHARING_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSHARING_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSHARING_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORSHARING_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-publiclink_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-publiclink_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORAGE_PUBLICLINK_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-shares_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-shares_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_SHARES_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_SHARES_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORAGE_SHARES_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORAGE_SHARES_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-system_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-system_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_SYSTEM_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_SYSTEM_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORAGE_SYSTEM_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORAGE_SYSTEM_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-users_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/storage-users_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORAGE_USERS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORAGE_USERS_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORAGE_USERS_LOG_PRETTY bool false Activates pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORAGE_USERS_LOG_COLOR bool false Activates colorized log output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/store_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/store_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDSTORE_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPESTORE_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTSTORE_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORSTORE_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELSTORE_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYSTORE_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORSTORE_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILESTORE_LOG_FILE string     STORE_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9464    STORE_DEBUG_TOKEN string     STORE_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    STORE_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    STORE_GRPC_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/thumbnails_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/thumbnails_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPETHUMBNAILS_TRACING_TYPE string  The tracing type.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint of the tracing service.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORTHUMBNAILS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The tracing collector.   OCIS_LOG_LEVELTHUMBNAILS_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYTHUMBNAILS_LOG_PRETTY bool false Enable pretty logs.   OCIS_LOG_COLORTHUMBNAILS_LOG_COLOR bool false Enable colored logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/users_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/users_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDUSERS_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Activates tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEUSERS_TRACING_TYPE string  The sampler type: remote, const, probabilistic, ratelimiting (default remote). See also https://www.jaegertracing.io/docs/latest/sampling/.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTUSERS_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The endpoint to the tracing collector.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORUSERS_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The HTTP endpoint for sending spans directly to a collector, i.e. http://jaeger-collector:14268/api/traces. If specified, the tracing endpoint is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/web_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/web_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEB_TRACING_ENABLED bool false    OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEB_TRACING_TYPE string     OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEB_TRACING_ENDPOINT string     OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEB_TRACING_COLLECTOR string     OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEB_LOG_LEVEL string     OCIS_LOG_PRETTYWEB_LOG_PRETTY bool false    OCIS_LOG_COLORWEB_LOG_COLOR bool false    OCIS_LOG_FILEWEB_LOG_FILE string     WEB_DEBUG_ADDR string 127.0.0.1:9104    WEB_DEBUG_TOKEN string     WEB_DEBUG_PPROF bool false    WEB_DEBUG_ZPAGES bool false    WEB_HTTP_ADDR string 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/webdav_configvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/_includes/webdav_configvars/</guid>
      <description>Environment Variables        Name Type Default Value Description     OCIS_TRACING_ENABLEDWEBDAV_TRACING_ENABLED bool false Enable tracing.   OCIS_TRACING_TYPEWEBDAV_TRACING_TYPE string  The tracing type.   OCIS_TRACING_ENDPOINTWEBDAV_TRACING_ENDPOINT string  The tracing service endpoint.   OCIS_TRACING_COLLECTORWEBDAV_TRACING_COLLECTOR string  The tracing collector.   OCIS_LOG_LEVELWEBDAV_LOG_LEVEL string  The log level.   OCIS_LOG_PRETTYWEBDAV_LOG_PRETTY bool false Enable pretty log output.   OCIS_LOG_COLORWEBDAV_LOG_COLOR bool false Enable colored log output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
