<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment Variables on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment Variables on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Envvar Naming Scopes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/envvar-naming-scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/envvar-naming-scopes/</guid>
      <description>Envvar Definition Naming Scope Local Envvars Global Envvars Reserved Envvar Names Lifecycle of Envvars Introduce new Envvars Adding Envvars to Existing Ones Deprecate Existing Envvars Separating Multiple Envvars The scope of an environment variable can be derived from its name. Therefore, it is important to follow the correct naming scheme to enable easy and proper identification. This is important when either:&#xA;a new local envvar is introduced. a new global envvar is added to an existing local envvar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Envvars</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/special-envvars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/special-envvars/</guid>
      <description>Special Scope Envvars Extended Envvars General Info Fixing Changed Items Handling these envvars properly is very important for the automated doc process for both the developer and the admin docs!&#xA;Special Scope Envvars Variables with special scope are only related to a deployment method such as OCIS_RUN_SERVICES. These variables cannot be gathered automatically, rarely change, can be viewed and must be maintained manually via the admin documentation.&#xA;Extended Envvars Environment variables with extended scope are not included in a service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Envvar Deprecation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/deprecating-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 15:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/deprecating-variables/</guid>
      <description>Deprecating Environment Variables Example What Happens Next? Deprecating Environment Variables Sometimes it is necessary to deprecate an environment variable to align the naming with conventions or remove it completely. We therefore added annotations to automate the documentation process.&#xA;The relevant annotations in the envvar struct tag are:&#xA;deprecationVersion&#xA;The release an envvar is announced for deprecation. removalVersion&#xA;The version it is finally going to be removed is defined via the mandatory placeholder %%NEXT_PRODUCTION_VERSION%%, not an actual version number.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Release Process for Envvars</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/new-release-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/general-info/envvars/new-release-process/</guid>
      <description>Special Scope Envvars Extended Envvars Ordinary Envvars Maintain env_vars.yaml Create Envvar Delta Files IMPORTANT&#xA;For a new ocis release, some tasks are necessary to be done before releasing. Follow the steps carefully to avoid issues. Most of the docs related tasks are not part of the CI. With each step finished successfully, the next step can be started. Sometimes, due to last minute changes, steps need to be redone!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
