<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WebDaV on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WebDaV on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 13:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Envrionment variables Commandline flags   Root Command Sub Commands  webdav version webdav health webdav server       Configuration oCIS Single Binary is not responsible for configuring extensions. Instead, each extension could either be configured by environment variables, cli flags or config files.
Each extension has its dedicated documentation page (e.g. https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis_proxy/configuration) which lists all possible configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Binaries   Configuration  Envrionment variables  Global Server Health   Commandline flags  Global Server Health   Configuration file   Usage  Server Health   Metrics       Installation So far we are offering two different variants for the installation. You can choose between Docker or pre-built binaries which are stored on our download mirrors and GitHub releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/webdav/building/</guid>
      <description>Backend       As this project is built with Go, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.12. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>