<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storage on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Provider</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesprovider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesprovider/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this.  Spaces Provider     A storage provider manages resourcesidentified by a referenceby accessing a storage systemwith a storage driver.
    oCIS spaces provider  [Software System]     oCIS spaces provider...      reva storage provider   [Component: golang]    hosts multiple storage spaces using a storage driver      reva storage provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces Registry</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesregistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spacesregistry/</guid>
      <description>The current implementation in oCIS might not yet fully reflect this concept. Feel free to add links to ADRs, PRs and Issues in short warning boxes like this.  Storage Space Registries     A storage spaces registry manages the namespacefor a user: it is used by clients to look up storage spaces a user has access to, the /dav/spaces endpoint to access it via WabDAV, and where the client should mount it in the users personal namespace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/apps/</guid>
      <description>oCIS is all about files. But most of the time you want to do something with files that is beyond the basic upload, download and share behavior. Therefore, oCIS has a concept for apps, that can handle specific file types, so called mime types.
App provider capability     The capabilities endpoint (eg. https://localhost:9200/ocs/v1.php/cloud/capabilities?format=json) gives you following capabilities which are relevant for the app provider:
{ &amp;#34;ocs&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;data&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;capabilities&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;files&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;app_providers&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;enabled&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage drivers</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/storagedrivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/storagedrivers/</guid>
      <description>A storage driver implements access to a storage system:
It maps the path and id based CS3 references to an appropriate storage systemspecific reference, e.g.:
 eos file ids posix inodes or paths deconstructed filesystem nodes  Storage providers     To manage the file tree oCIS uses storage providers that are accessing the underlying storage using a storage driver. The driver can be used to change the implementation of a storage aspect to better reflect the actual underlying storage capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/namespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/namespaces/</guid>
      <description>A namespace is a set of paths with a common prefix. Depending on the endpoint you are talking to you will encounter a different kind of namespace: In ownCloud 10 all paths are considered relative to the users home. The CS3 API uses a global namespace and the storage providers use a local namespace with paths relative to the storage providers root.
    /rel/path/to/file.ext     /rel/p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/users/</guid>
      <description>TODO add this to the storage overview? or is this a different part? That should be started as a separate service ? And documented elsewhere, eg. in the accounts?
User and Group provisioning     In oc10 users are identified by a username, which cannot change, because it is used as a foreign key in several tables. For oCIS we are internally identifying users by a UUID, while using the username in the WebDAV and OCS APIs for backwards compatability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminology</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/terminology/</guid>
      <description>Communication is hard. And clear communication is even harder. You may encounter the following terms throughout the documentation, in the code or when talking to other developers. Just keep in mind that whenever you hear or read storage, that term needs to be clarified, because on its own it is too vague. PR welcome.
Logical concepts     Resources     A resource is the basic building block that oCIS manages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Changes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/proposedchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/proposedchanges/</guid>
      <description>Some architectural changes still need to be clarified or changed. Maybe an ADR is in order for all of the below.
Reva Gateway changes     A dedicated shares storage provider     Currently, when a user accepts a share, a cs3 reference is created in the users /home/shares folder. This reference represents the mount point of a share and can be renamed, similar to the share jail in ownCloud 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaces</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/spaces/</guid>
      <description>Editing a Storage Space  Updating a space property Updating a space description Quotas  Quota Enforcement  Considerations       Storage Spaces Shares Notes      Editing a Storage Space     The OData specification allows for a mirage of ways of addressing an entity. We will support addressing a Drive entity by its unique identifier, which is the one the graph-api returns when listing spaces, and its format is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ports</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/storage/ports/</guid>
      <description>Currently, every service needs to be configured with a port so oCIS can start them on localhost. We will automate this by using a service registry for more services, until eventually only the proxy has to be configured with a public port.
For now, the storage service uses these ports to preconfigure those services:
   port service     9109 health, used by cli?   9140 frontend   9141 frontend debug   9142 gateway   9143 gateway debug   9144 users   9145 users debug   9146 authbasic   9147 authbasic debug   9148 authbearer   9149 authbearer debug   9150 sharing   9151 sharing debug   9154 storage home grpc   9155 storage home http   9156 storage home debug   9157 storage users grpc   9158 storage users http   9159 storage users debug   9160 groups   9161 groups debug   9164 storage appprovider   9165 storage appprovider debug   9178 storage public link   9179 storage public link data   9215 storage meta grpc   9216 storage meta http   9217 storage meta debug    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
