<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adrs on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adrs on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/adr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0001-introduce-accounts-service/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduce an accounts service  Status: superseded by ADR-0003  Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm, @micbar, @pmaier1  Date: 2020-06-15   Technical Story: persist accounts Context and Problem Statement To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email und username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes. While there is an account porting protocol that describes how a relying party (RP) such as ownCloud should behave, it still requires the RP to maintain its own user identifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0002-persist-accounts-using-cs3-storage/</guid>
      <description>2. Persist accounts in a CS3 storage  Status: accepted  Deciders: @butonic, @felixboehm  Date: 2020-08-21   Technical Story: File system based indexing Context and Problem Statement To set up High Availability (HA) or a geo-replicated setup we need to persist accounts in a distributed way. To efficiently query the accounts by email or username, and not only by id, they need to be indexed. Unfortunately, the bleve index we currently store locally on disk cannot be shared by multiple instances, preventing a scale out deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0003-external-user-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/adr/0003-external-user-management/</guid>
      <description>3. Use external User Management  Status: accepted  Deciders: @butonic, @micbar, @dragotin, @hodyroff, @pmaier1  Date: 2020-12-09   Technical Story: Skip account-service by talking to CS3 user-api Context and Problem Statement To attach metadata like shares to users ownCloud relies on persistent, non-reassignable, unique identifiers for users (and files). Email and username can change when a user changes his name. But even the OIDC sub+iss combination may change when the IdP changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>