<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ownCloud Web on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ownCloud Web on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Source Code Installation Docker Configuration Options Scripts and Styles Sentry Setting up backend and running Running Source Code The source code is hosted at https://github.com/owncloud/web. Please refer to the build documentation for Web.&#xA;Installation Make sure to have Docker, Docker-Compose, Node.js and pnpm installed. If you plan to work with translations, you also need to install the Transifex Client. Note when installing the Transifex Client, change to your ~/.local/bin directory first because it installs at the current location.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building From Source</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</guid>
      <description>Building ownCloud Web Updating Dependencies Building the Documentation Prerequisites Run a Docs Build Viewing the Documentation Deploying the documentation Building Information Building ownCloud Web Run pnpm install to install dependencies Run pnpm build to build Web and all apps included in the packages folder Updating Dependencies Do not update dependencies by yourself but use the provided ones by the repo. When rebasing your local clone, you can always run pnpm install to be in sync with the defined dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup With ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</guid>
      <description>Compatibility Prerequisites Setting up the ownCloud Server Adjusting config.php Setting up OAuth2 Setting up Web Running Web Running acceptance tests Compatibility Please note that the usage of Web UI and ownCloud 10 as backend is not recommended starting with version 7.1.0 of the Web UI. Therefore, this section only applies to versions &amp;lt; 7.1.0.&#xA;Prerequisites Decide on which host and port Web will be served, for example https://web-host:9100/web-path/. In this document, we will refer to the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup With oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Web Running Web Setting up oCIS Start oCIS Running tests Setting up Web Clone the repository Initally install all dependencies by running pnpm install Copy ./config/config.json.sample-ocis to ./config/config.json and adjust values if required Running Web Start bundling web with a watcher by running pnpm build:w Setting up oCIS Setup oCIS by following the setup instructions Start oCIS with local links to your bundled web frontend and config by running WEB_ASSET_CORE_PATH=.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
