<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ownCloud Web on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ownCloud Web on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation Docker Source Code Configuration Options Scripts and Styles Sentry Setting up backend and running Running Installation Docker Make sure to have Docker, Docker-Compose, Node.js and pnpm installed.
This setup currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t work on Windows out of the box.
Workaround One of our contributors has opened a PR to a dependency that prevents us from successfully bundling the frontend. Feel free to check out [his changes](https://github.com/egoist/rollup-plugin-postcss/pull/384) and build them locally if you absolutely want to work on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building from source</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/building/</guid>
      <description>Building ownCloud Web Updating dependencies Building the documentation Setting up Viewing the documentation Deploying the documentation Building ownCloud Web Run pnpm install to install dependencies Run pnpm build to build Web and all apps included in the packages folder Updating dependencies Run pnpm upgrade to update dependencies Building the documentation Setting up Install hugo Run make docs Viewing the documentation To view the rendered docs in the browser run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing ownCloud Web Versioning Release Guide Next steps Releasing ownCloud Web OwnCloud Web can be hosted standalone for a dedicated oCIS backend or bundled as part of oCIS.
Versioning We follow the Semantic Versioning scheme. Therefore, each change is of one of the possible types: Bugfix, Change, Enhancement, Security.
The highest type before a new release determines the version update number, so if it&amp;rsquo;s only Bugfix and Security changes the next release will be a PATCH version bump, if there&amp;rsquo;s at least one Enhancement within the changes this leads to a MINOR version bump, while Change type changes make for a new MAJOR release version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-oc10/</guid>
      <description>Compatibility Prerequisites Setting up the ownCloud Server Adjusting config.php Setting up OAuth2 Setting up Web Running Web Running acceptance tests Compatibility Please note that the usage of Web UI and ownCloud 10 as backend is not recommended starting with version 7.1.0 of the Web UI. Therefore, this section only applies to versions &amp;lt; 7.1.0.
Prerequisites Decide on which host and port Web will be served, for example https://web-host:9100/web-path/. In this document, we will refer to the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with oCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/backend-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Web Running Web Setting up oCIS Start oCIS Running tests Setting up Web Clone the repository Initally install all dependencies by running pnpm install Copy ./config/config.json.sample-ocis to ./config/config.json and adjust values if required Running Web Start bundling web with a watcher by running pnpm build:w Setting up oCIS Setup oCIS by following the setup instructions Start oCIS with local links to your bundled web frontend and config by running WEB_ASSET_CORE_PATH=.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
