<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phoenix on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phoenix on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Binaries Source code   Setting up backend and running Running     Installation Docker TBD
Binaries TBD
Source code The source code is hosted at https://github.com/owncloud/phoenix Please refer to the build documentation for Phoenix.
Setting up backend and running Phoenix can run against either ownCloud 10 as backend or OCIS. Depending which one you chose, please check the matching section:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building from source</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/building/</guid>
      <description>Building Phoenix Updating dependencies Cleaning up the workspace Buildling the documentation  Setting up Viewing the documentation Deploying the documentation       Building Phoenix  Run yarn install to install core dependencies Run yarn install-all to install dependencies of all apps and core Run yarn dist to build Phoenix and all apps included in the apps folder  Updating dependencies  Run yarn upgrade-all to update core and app dependencies  Cleaning up the workspace  Run yarn clean-all to remove node_modules and dist folder  Buildling the documentation Setting up  Install hugo Run make docs  Viewing the documentation To view the rendered docs in the browser run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with ownCloud 10</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/backend-oc10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/backend-oc10/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Setting up the ownCloud Server  Adjusting config.php Setting up OAuth2 Setting up Phoenix   Running Phoenix Running acceptance tests     Prerequisites Decide on which host and port Phoenix will be served, for example https://phoenix-host:8300/phoenix-path/. In this document, we will refer to the following:
 &amp;lt;phoenix-url&amp;gt; as the full URL, for example https://phoenix-host:8300/phoenix-path/ &amp;lt;phoenix-domain&amp;gt; as the protocol, domain and port, for example: https://phoenix-host:8300  Setting up the ownCloud Server Make sure you have an ownCloud Server already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup with OCIS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/backend-ocis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/backend-ocis/</guid>
      <description>Setting up OCIS services Setting up Phoenix Setting up ocis-phoenix service Running Phoenix Running acceptance tests     Setting up OCIS services  Setup OCIS by cloning the ocis repository and following the setup instructions there. Do not start the whole server but run ./bin/ocis --log-level debug $EXTENSION for all the existing extensions except the phoenix service. A list of extensions can be found by running .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running acceptance tests</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/testing/</guid>
      <description>Setting up Selenium  Setup using Docker Setup using Docker Desktop for Mac Setup using standalone Selenium server   run tests  with ownCloud 10 backend with OCIS backend   Available settings to be set by environment variables     Setting up Selenium There are multiple ways to run Selenium:
 Setup using Docker Setup using Docker Desktop for Mac Setup using a standalone Selenium server  Setup using Docker  Set the environment variables SELENIUM_HOST as localhost and SERVER_HOST in the format http://&amp;lt;ip_addr&amp;gt;:9100.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the documentation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/building-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/clients/web/building-docs/</guid>
      <description>Buildling the documentation  Setting up Viewing the documentation Deploying the documentation       Buildling the documentation Setting up  Install hugo Run make docs  Viewing the documentation To view the rendered docs in the browser run:
cd hugo hugo -D server Then open &amp;ldquo;http://localhost:1313/&amp;rdquo;
When making changes to the docs, run make docs again and the server will pick up the changes and reload the page automatically</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>