<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Run oCIS  Binaries Docker   Usage  Login to oCIS Web Basic Commands       Run oCIS We are distributing oCIS as binaries and Docker images.
You can find more deployments examples in the deployment section
Binaries The binaries for different platforms are downloadable at our download mirror or on GitHub. Latest binaries from the master branch can be found at our download mirrors testing section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/eos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/eos/</guid>
      <description>Docker dev environment for eos storage  1. Start eos &amp;amp; ocis containers 2. LDAP support 3. Home storage 4. Users storage 5. Metadata storage 6. Accounts service   Verification Further exploration Cleaning up Troubleshooting  Docker-compose exits right away Where are the logs ? How do I update a service in the ocis container? Creation and upload of files does not work Uploading big files appears to hang Running out of space quickly       oCIS can be configured to run on top of eos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/extensions/</guid>
      <description>How to build and run ocis-simple Hacking ocis-hello  Option 1:   Hacking phoenix (and ocis-phoenix) The ownCloud design system External phoenix apps Phoenix extension points  Phoenix core Files app   API driven development     How to build and run ocis-simple ocis uses build tags to build different flavors of the binary. In order to work on a new extension we are going to reduce the scope a little and use the simple tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Login Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/login-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/login-flow/</guid>
      <description>Login Flow The following sequence diagram describes the openid connect auth code flow. The eight numbered steps and notes correspond to the openid connect auth code flow steps. Example requests are based on the spec as well.:
  mermaid.initialize({ flowchart: { useMaxWidth: true } });  sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ %% this documents the login workflow %% examples taken from the oidc spec https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#CodeFlowAuth %% TODO add PKCE, see https://developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/metrics/</guid>
      <description>Metrics This service provides some Prometheus metrics through the debug endpoint, you can optionally secure the metrics endpoint by some random token, which got to be configured through one of the flag --debug-token or the environment variable OCIS_DEBUG_TOKEN mentioned above. By default the metrics endpoint is bound to http://0.0.0.0:8001/metrics.
 go_gc_duration_seconds A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_sum A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_count A summary of the GC invocation durations go_goroutines Number of goroutines that currently exist go_info Information about the Go environment go_memstats_alloc_bytes Number of bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_alloc_bytes_total Total number of bytes allocated, even if freed go_memstats_buck_hash_sys_bytes Number of bytes used by the profiling bucket hash table go_memstats_frees_total Total number of frees go_memstats_gc_cpu_fraction The fraction of this program&amp;rsquo;s available CPU time used by the GC since the program started go_memstats_gc_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for garbage collection system metadata go_memstats_heap_alloc_bytes Number of heap bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_heap_idle_bytes Number of heap bytes waiting to be used go_memstats_heap_inuse_bytes Number of heap bytes that are in use go_memstats_heap_objects Number of allocated objects go_memstats_heap_released_bytes Number of heap bytes released to OS go_memstats_heap_sys_bytes Number of heap bytes obtained from system go_memstats_last_gc_time_seconds Number of seconds since 1970 of last garbage collection go_memstats_lookups_total Total number of pointer lookups go_memstats_mallocs_total Total number of mallocs go_memstats_mcache_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mcache structures go_memstats_mcache_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mcache structures obtained from system go_memstats_mspan_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mspan structures go_memstats_mspan_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mspan structures obtained from system go_memstats_next_gc_bytes Number of heap bytes when next garbage collection will take place go_memstats_other_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for other system allocations go_memstats_stack_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by the stack allocator go_memstats_stack_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system for stack allocator go_memstats_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system go_threads Number of OS threads created promhttp_metric_handler_requests_in_flight Current number of scrapes being served promhttp_metric_handler_requests_total Total number of scrapes by HTTP status code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/request-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/request-flow/</guid>
      <description>Request Flow The following sequence diagram describes the general request flow. It shows where account provisioning and token minting are happening:
  mermaid.initialize({ flowchart: { useMaxWidth: true } });  sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as corporate LDAP server user-+client: What is the content of my home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public upload Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/public-upload-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/public-upload-flow/</guid>
      <description>Public Upload flow The following diagram describes the flow of requests:
ocis-reva sharing
REVA_SHARING_ADDR = 0.0.0.0:9150
ocis-reva sharing...ocis-reva frontend
REVA_FRONTEND_ADDR = 0.0.0.0:9140
REVA_GATEWAY_URL = ocis:9142
ocis-reva frontend...ocis-proxy
PROXY_HTTP_ADDR = 0.0.0.0:9200
ocis-proxy...2  POST http://ocis:9140/remote.php/dav/files/einstein/2 POST http:/...ocdav
prefix = &#34;&#34;
timeout = 86400
ocdav...datagateway
prefix = &#34;data&#34;
timeout = 86400
datagateway...client
client&amp;#xa;22  PATCH https://oc.example.org/data/{token}
Tus-Resumable: 1.0.022 PATCH http...ocis-reva gateway
REVA_GATEWAY_ADDR = 0.0.0.0:9142
ocis-reva gateway...storage-registry
storage-registry&amp;#xa;Expose: trueExpose: true24  PATCH http://ocis:9156/data/u-u-i-d24 PATCH http.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/license/</guid>
      <description>This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>