<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/ocis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:03:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/config/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Framework Overview of the approach In-depth configuration Flows Examples Expected loading locations Only config files Using ENV variables Substitute ENV variables in configuration files Workflows Supervised Unsupervised Shared Values Log config keys Default config values (in yaml) Configuration Framework In order to simplify deployments and development the configuration model from oCIS aims to be simple yet flexible.
Overview of the approach In-depth configuration Since we include a set of predefined extensions within the single binary, configuring an extension can be done in a variety of ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup Considerations</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 10:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/backup/</guid>
      <description>This small guide aims to shed some light on the internal Infinite Scale data structure. You can refer to it when you are trying to optimize your backups or if you are just curious about how Infinite Scale stores its data.
Note, as a prerequisite backing up Infinite Scale, the instance has to be fully shut down for the time being.
Ocis Data Structure Ocis stores its data in a folder that can be configured via the environment variable OCIS_BASE_DATA_PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Registry Discovery</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 14:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage_registry_discovery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In order for an oCIS client to access oCIS storage spaces for an End-User, the client needs to know where the oCIS instance is. oCIS uses WebFinger RFC7033 to locate the oCIS instance for an End-User.
This discovery is optional. If the client has another way of discovering the OpenID instance, e.g. when logging in with a username a static domain might be configured or the domain in the URL might be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 16:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/migration/</guid>
      <description>The migration happens in subsequent stages while the service is online. First all users need to migrate to the new architecture, then the global namespace needs to be introduced. Finally, the data on disk can be migrated user by user by switching the storage driver.
@jfd: It might be easier to introduce the spaces api in oc10 and then migrate to oCIS. We cannot migrate both at the same time, the architecture to oCIS (which will change fileids) and introduce a global namespace (which requires stable fileids to let clients handle moves without redownloading).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/metrics/</guid>
      <description> Metrics This service provides some Prometheus metrics through the debug endpoint, you can optionally secure the metrics endpoint by some random token, which has to be configured either through the flag --debug-token or the environment variable OCIS_DEBUG_TOKEN mentioned above. By default, the metrics endpoint is bound to http://0.0.0.0:8001/metrics.
go_gc_duration_seconds A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_sum A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_count A summary of the GC invocation durations go_goroutines Number of goroutines that currently exist go_info Information about the Go environment go_memstats_alloc_bytes Number of bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_alloc_bytes_total Total number of bytes allocated, even if freed go_memstats_buck_hash_sys_bytes Number of bytes used by the profiling bucket hash table go_memstats_frees_total Total number of frees go_memstats_gc_cpu_fraction The fraction of this program&amp;rsquo;s available CPU time used by the GC since the program started go_memstats_gc_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for garbage collection system metadata go_memstats_heap_alloc_bytes Number of heap bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_heap_idle_bytes Number of heap bytes waiting to be used go_memstats_heap_inuse_bytes Number of heap bytes that are in use go_memstats_heap_objects Number of allocated objects go_memstats_heap_released_bytes Number of heap bytes released to OS go_memstats_heap_sys_bytes Number of heap bytes obtained from system go_memstats_last_gc_time_seconds Number of seconds since 1970 of last garbage collection go_memstats_lookups_total Total number of pointer lookups go_memstats_mallocs_total Total number of mallocs go_memstats_mcache_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mcache structures go_memstats_mcache_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mcache structures obtained from system go_memstats_mspan_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mspan structures go_memstats_mspan_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mspan structures obtained from system go_memstats_next_gc_bytes Number of heap bytes when next garbage collection will take place go_memstats_other_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for other system allocations go_memstats_stack_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by the stack allocator go_memstats_stack_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system for stack allocator go_memstats_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system go_threads Number of OS threads created promhttp_metric_handler_requests_in_flight Current number of scrapes being served promhttp_metric_handler_requests_total Total number of scrapes by HTTP status code </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/license/</guid>
      <description>The source code of the project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.
Stable, supported binary builds of ownCloud Infinite Scale that will be distributed by ownCloud GmbH are covered by a non OSS Freemium License EULA. This protects additional efforts that ownCloud GmbH is putting into these builds.
Since the source code of Infinite Scale is available under free licenses, the free usage can, should and will not be limited in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 21:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Releases Release Flavours Documentation Updating and Overlap Support Versioning Scheme Releases Release Date Flavour Version Notes Support 23.12.2024 Rolling - - - 02.12.2024 Rolling - - - 11.11.2024 Production - - - 21.10.2024 Rolling - - - 30.09.2024 Rolling - - - 09.09.2024 Rolling - - - 19.08.2024 Rolling - - - 29.07.2024 Rolling - - - 08.07.2024 Rolling - - - 17.06.2024 Rolling - - - 27.05.2024 Rolling - - - 02.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/release_notes/</guid>
      <description>The Infinite Scale Release Notes have been moved and are published with the ownCloud Documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
