<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oCIS - ownCloud Infinite Scale on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Commandline flags   Root Command Sub Commands  ocis kill ocis run ocis health ocis list ocis server List of available Extension subcommands  ocis storage-userprovider ocis storage-home ocis idp ocis storage-users ocis accounts ocis onlyoffice ocis proxy ocis storage-gateway ocis storage-public-link ocis version ocis glauth ocis ocs ocis storage-frontend ocis storage-groupprovider ocis storage-metadata ocis settings ocis storage-auth-basic ocis storage-auth-bearer ocis web ocis webdav ocis storage-sharing ocis store ocis thumbnails         Configuration oCIS Single Binary is not responsible for configuring extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/metrics/</guid>
      <description>Metrics This service provides some Prometheus metrics through the debug endpoint, you can optionally secure the metrics endpoint by some random token, which got to be configured through one of the flag --debug-token or the environment variable OCIS_DEBUG_TOKEN mentioned above. By default the metrics endpoint is bound to http://0.0.0.0:8001/metrics.
 go_gc_duration_seconds A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_sum A summary of the GC invocation durations go_gc_duration_seconds_count A summary of the GC invocation durations go_goroutines Number of goroutines that currently exist go_info Information about the Go environment go_memstats_alloc_bytes Number of bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_alloc_bytes_total Total number of bytes allocated, even if freed go_memstats_buck_hash_sys_bytes Number of bytes used by the profiling bucket hash table go_memstats_frees_total Total number of frees go_memstats_gc_cpu_fraction The fraction of this program&amp;rsquo;s available CPU time used by the GC since the program started go_memstats_gc_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for garbage collection system metadata go_memstats_heap_alloc_bytes Number of heap bytes allocated and still in use go_memstats_heap_idle_bytes Number of heap bytes waiting to be used go_memstats_heap_inuse_bytes Number of heap bytes that are in use go_memstats_heap_objects Number of allocated objects go_memstats_heap_released_bytes Number of heap bytes released to OS go_memstats_heap_sys_bytes Number of heap bytes obtained from system go_memstats_last_gc_time_seconds Number of seconds since 1970 of last garbage collection go_memstats_lookups_total Total number of pointer lookups go_memstats_mallocs_total Total number of mallocs go_memstats_mcache_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mcache structures go_memstats_mcache_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mcache structures obtained from system go_memstats_mspan_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by mspan structures go_memstats_mspan_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for mspan structures obtained from system go_memstats_next_gc_bytes Number of heap bytes when next garbage collection will take place go_memstats_other_sys_bytes Number of bytes used for other system allocations go_memstats_stack_inuse_bytes Number of bytes in use by the stack allocator go_memstats_stack_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system for stack allocator go_memstats_sys_bytes Number of bytes obtained from system go_threads Number of OS threads created promhttp_metric_handler_requests_in_flight Current number of scrapes being served promhttp_metric_handler_requests_total Total number of scrapes by HTTP status code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/license/</guid>
      <description>This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/release_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/release_notes/</guid>
      <description>ownCloud Infinite Scale 1.2.0 Technology Preview Version 1.2.0 brings more functionality and stability to ownCloud Infinite Scale. ownCloud Web now loads a lot faster and is prepared for the introduction of accessibility features. An initial implementation for S3 storage support is available and file integrity checking has been introduced.
The most prominent changes in version 1.2.0 comprise:
 The initial loading time for ownCloud Web has been reduced by handling dependencies more efficiently (the bundle size of ownCloud Web has been drastically reduced) https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/release_roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/release_roadmap/</guid>
      <description>You may have asked yourself why there are major version 1 tags in our GitHub repository but the readme still states ownCloud Infinite Scale is currently in a technical preview state. It will be subject to a lot of changes and is not yet ready for general production deployments.. How can that be if its a major version 1?
Our initial and also our current plan is to stick to SemVer as versioning scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/ocis/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Run oCIS  Binaries Docker   Usage  Login to ownCloud Web Basic Management Commands       Run oCIS We are distributing oCIS as binaries and Docker images.
You can find more deployments examples in the deployment section
Binaries You can find the latest official release of ocis at our download mirror or on GitHub. The latest build from the master branch can be found at our download mirrors testing section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>