<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Settings on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Settings on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 14:47:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Service Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Example YAML Config 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 # Autogenerated # Filename: settings-config-example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Bundles</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/bundles/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Bundle is a collection of settings, uniquely identified by the key of the extension registering the bundle and the key of the bundle itself. Its purpose is to let oCIS services define settings and make them available to users. They are dynamically rendered into forms, available in the frontend.
As of now we support five different types of settings:
boolean integer string single choice list of integers or strings multiple choice list of integers or strings Each Setting is uniquely identified by a key within the bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Values</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/values/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Value is the value an authenticated user has chosen for a specific setting, defined in a settings bundle.
Identifying settings values A settings value is uniquely identified by four attributes. Three of them are coming from the definition of the setting within it&amp;rsquo;s settings bundle (see Settings Bundles for an example). The fourth identifies the user.
extension: Key of the extension that registered the settings bundle, bundleKey: Key of the settings bundle, settingKey: Key of the setting as defined within the bundle, accountUuid: The UUID of the authenticated user who has saved the setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/services/settings/glossary/</guid>
      <description>In the context of this extension and oCIS in general, we are using the following terminology.
Configuration System configuration e.g. service host names and ports Changes need to be propagated to other services Typically modified on the CLI Settings Application level settings e.g. default language Can be modified at runtime without restarting the service Preferences User settings Subset of &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; e.g. preferred language of a user Settings Bundle Collection of related settings Registered by an oCIS extension Settings Value Manifestation of a setting for a specific user E.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
