<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oCIS Web on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oCIS Web on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Binaries   Configuration  Environment variables  Global Server Health   Commandline flags  Global Server Health   Configuration file   Usage  Server Health   Metrics     Installation So far we are offering two different variants for the installation. You can choose between Docker or pre-built binaries which are stored on our download mirrors and GitHub releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/building/</guid>
      <description>Backend cd ocis-phoenix make generate make build The above commands will download a Phoenix release and embed it into the binary. Finally you should have the binary within the bin/ folder now, give it a try with ./bin/ocis-phoenix -h to see all available options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Releasing</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/releasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/releasing/</guid>
      <description>Releasing  Package Hierarchy  Prerequisites Updating ocis-phoenix Next steps         Releasing The next generation Web Frontend is shipped as an oCIS Extension. The ocis-phoenix extension is also embedded in the single binary and part of the ocis server command.
To update this package within all the deliveries, we need to update the package in the following chain from the bottom to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/ocis-phoenix/license/</guid>
      <description>This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>