<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flow documentation on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flow documentation on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Login Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/login-flow/</guid>
      <description>Login Flow The following sequence diagram describes the openid connect auth code flow. The eight numbered steps and notes correspond to the openid connect auth code flow steps. Example requests are based on the spec as well:
sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ %% this documents the login workflow %% examples taken from the oidc spec https://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-core-1_0.html#CodeFlowAuth %% TODO add PKCE, see https://developer.okta.com/blog/2019/08/22/okta-authjs-pkce#use-pkce-to-make-your-apps-more-secure participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant idm as LibreIDM participant ldap as External User Directory user-&gt;&gt;+client: What is the content of my home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/request-flow/</guid>
      <description>Request Flow The following sequence diagram describes the general request flow. It shows where account provisioning and token minting are happening:
sequenceDiagram %% we have comments!! \o/ participant user as User participant client as Client participant proxy as ocis-proxy participant idp as IdP participant accounts as ocis-accounts participant ldap as corporate LDAP server user-&gt;&gt;+client: What is the content of my home? client-&gt;&gt;+proxy: PROPFIND Bearer auth using oidc auth token Note over client,proxy: What is in a bearer token?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public upload Flow</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 14:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/flow-docs/public-upload-flow/</guid>
      <description>Public Upload flow The following diagram describes the flow of requests:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
