<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conventions</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/conventions/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to ownCloud Web Linting and Tests Changelog Items Code Conventions Early Returns Translations TypeScript Vue 3 and Composition API Dependencies This is a collection of tips and conventions to follow when working on the ownCloud web frontend. Since it is a living document, please open a PR if you find something missing.
Contributing to ownCloud Web Everyone is invited to contribute. Simply fork the codebase, check the issues for a suitable one and open a pull request!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repo structure and (published) packages</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/repo-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/repo-structure/</guid>
      <description>Repository Structure dev Folder and docker-compose.yml File docs Folder packages Folder tests Folder package.json File vite.config.ts (Published) Packages Code Style and Build Config ownCloud Design System web-client web-pkg web-runtime Standalone Core Apps Viewer and Editor Apps Testing Repository Structure From a developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective, the most important parts of the ownCloud Web repo are the following files and folders:
dev Folder and docker-compose.yml File The /dev folder contains all the configuration files that are needed in the docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/clients/web/development/tooling/</guid>
      <description>Packaging Development Setup Prerequisites Installing Dependencies Starting the Server Building and Accessing Web Using Instant Hot-Reload via Vite Running Web with oC10 Packaging Web is using pnpm as package manager and vite as build tool. The latter is built on top of rollup and brings some additional features such as instant hot-reloading.
Development Setup Prerequisites docker docker-compose (if not already included in your docker installation) pnpm node If you’re not using Docker Desktop, you might have to modify your /etc/hosts and add 127.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
