<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>oCIS and Containers</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-and-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-and-containers/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Native Why do we recommend to work with containers?
Lightweight Containers are more lightweight than VMs. It is easier to work with shared volumes and networks because they are isolated from the host system. Dependencies The container images have all dependencies installed and the maintainer takes care for keeping them up-to-date. Scaling In addition to that, containers help with scaling. You can run multiple instances of one container and distribute them across hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalistic Evaluation Guide for oCIS with Docker</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-mini-eval/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-mini-eval/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites What you can Expect Setup Procedure Prepare Paths Pull the Image First Time Initialisation Recurring Start of Infinite Scale Access Infinite Scale with the Browser Remove the Evaluation Next Steps IMPORTANT This type of installation is ONLY intended for a quick evaluation and to access the instance from your local machine using internal certificates only. We recommend using test data only for this evaluation.
Prerequisites As a prerequisite, we assume you have Docker installed locally on a machine that has a GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover oCIS with Docker</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-local-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/ocis-local-docker/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Start oCIS with docker compose Create the project Initialize Mount the config file Apply the changes Open the port 9200 to the outside Persist data, restart and logging Pin the oCIS version Wrapping up Prerequisites Local docker installation (e.g. Docker for Desktop) Check oCIS and Containers Start oCIS with docker compose Create the project Use the following skeleton as a docker-compose.yml:
mkdir simple-ocis &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ cd simple-ocis &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ touch docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Data using rclone</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/migrate-data-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 14:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/guides/migrate-data-rclone/</guid>
      <description>People keep asking on how to migrate data from other cloud storage to Infinite Scale.
There are too many cloud variants and use cases out there to have a migration path for all at hand, but let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can start with: There is the famous Swiss army knife for clouds called rclone available.
The awesome rclone tool makes it easy to migrate data from one installation to another on a user per user base.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
