<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proxy on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proxy on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 09:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/about/</guid>
      <description>This service provides an proxy service that routes requests to the correct services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Binaries   Usage  Server Version       Installation So far we are offering two different variants for the installation. You can choose between Docker or pre-built binaries which are stored on our download mirrors and GitHub releases. Maybe we will also provide system packages for the major distributions later if we see the need for it.
Docker Docker images for ocis-reva are hosted on https://hub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 09:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Commandline flags proxy health proxy ocis-proxy proxy server proxy version       Configuration oCIS Single Binary is not responsible for configuring extensions. Instead, each extension could either be configured by environment variables, cli flags or config files.
Each extension has its dedicated documentation page (e.g. https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/configuration/) which lists all possible configurations. Config files and environment variables are picked up if you use the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/proxy/building/</guid>
      <description>Backend     As this project is built with Go, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.13. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:
git clone https://github.com/owncloud/ocis-proxy.git cd ocis-proxy All required tool besides Go itself and make are bundled or getting automatically installed within the GOPATH.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>