<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>File Picker on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in File Picker on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 10:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Components of the File picker  File picker Location picker        ownCloud File picker is a web component which can be integrated into existing web applications. It connects to an ownCloud server and enables a user to select resources which are then provided in a response of a fired event. Visit installation to see how to integrate the File picker into your product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/installation/</guid>
      <description>Setup authentication  OpenID Connect config OAuth2 config Pass bearer token   Install File picker package Select browser storage Integrate in HTML page with vanilla JavaScript Integrate in Vue web application Set correct variation Theming Buttons and events  Select button Cancel button        Setup authentication     The config for the server backend and authentication needs to be provided in json format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Resources</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/accessing-resources/</guid>
      <description>Access resources Perform actions with selected resources      If using File picker as a web component, it is returning selected resources via events called select and update. To access them, you need to set an event listener where you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to get them as part of the response of the callback function.
Access resources     &amp;lt;file-picker id=&amp;#34;file-picker&amp;#34; variation=&amp;#34;resource&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/file-picker&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; const item = document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/customisations/</guid>
      <description>Variation  File Picker Location Picker   Actions  Select Cancel        It is possible to customise certain parts of the File Picker with the help of props.
Variation     File picker comes in two different variations - File Picker and Location Picker. To specify which one should be used, set property variation to resource or location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Component reference</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/component-reference/</guid>
      <description>Props Events      &amp;lt;file-picker&amp;gt; Props        Property Type Default Description     variation String  Specifies if File Picker (resource) or Location Picker (location) should be used   configLocation String window.location.origin + &#39;/file-picker-config.json&#39; Defines where the config file should be located   bearerToken String null Bearer token used for requests authentication. If specified, authorization step is skipped   configObject `String Object`    isSdkProvided Boolean false Asserts whether ownCloud SDK is already initialised in the consuming app   selectBtnLabel String null Replaces the select button label   isSelectBtnDisplayed Boolean true Asserts whether the select button should be displayed   cancelBtnLabel String nulll Displays the cancel button and uses the given value as a label   isOdsProvided Boolean false Asserts whether the ownCloud Design System has been already initialised in the consuming app   locale String null Sets the language in which the File Picker should be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Management</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/integration/file_picker/focus-management/</guid>
      <description>Focusing content of File Picker Initial folder load focus      File Picker comes only with partial focus management. If you want to focus an element, it needs to be achieved through a code in the consuming app.
Focusing content of File Picker     If you&amp;rsquo;re including File Picker as a web component, managing focus is slightly different from focusing content of any other component in the DOM tree.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
