<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gRPC on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gRPC on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto CS3Source WebdavSource ThumbnailType Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto CS3Source Field Type Label Description path string authorization string WebdavSource Field Type Label Description url string REQUIRED. is_public_link bool REQUIRED. webdav_authorization string OPTIONAL. reva_authorization string OPTIONAL. public_link_token string OPTIONAL. ThumbnailType The file types to which the thumbnail can be encoded to.
Name Number Description PNG 0 Represents PNG type JPG 1 Represents JPG type GIF 2 Represents GIF type Scalar Value Types .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.eventhistory.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_eventhistory_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_eventhistory_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto GetEventsForUserRequest GetEventsRequest GetEventsResponse EventHistoryService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto GetEventsForUserRequest A request to retrieve events belonging to a userID
Field Type Label Description userID string the userID of the events we want to get GetEventsRequest A request to retrieve events
Field Type Label Description ids string repeated the ids of the events we want to get GetEventsResponse The service response
Field Type Label Description events ocis.messages.eventhistory.v0.Event repeated EventHistoryService A Service for storing events</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto AddSettingToBundleRequest AddSettingToBundleResponse AssignRoleToUserRequest AssignRoleToUserResponse GetBundleRequest GetBundleResponse GetPermissionByIDRequest GetPermissionByIDResponse GetValueByUniqueIdentifiersRequest GetValueRequest GetValueResponse ListBundlesRequest ListBundlesResponse ListPermissionsByResourceRequest ListPermissionsByResourceResponse ListPermissionsRequest ListPermissionsResponse ListRoleAssignmentsRequest ListRoleAssignmentsResponse ListValuesRequest ListValuesResponse RemoveRoleFromUserRequest RemoveSettingFromBundleRequest SaveBundleRequest requests and responses for settings bundles SaveBundleResponse SaveValueRequest SaveValueResponse BundleService PermissionService RoleService ValueService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/settings/v0/settings.proto AddSettingToBundleRequest Field Type Label Description bundle_id string setting ocis.messages.settings.v0.Setting AddSettingToBundleResponse Field Type Label Description setting ocis.messages.settings.v0.Setting AssignRoleToUserRequest Field Type Label Description account_uuid string role_id string the role_id is a bundle_id internally AssignRoleToUserResponse Field Type Label Description assignment ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.thumbnails.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_thumbnails_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto GetThumbnailRequest GetThumbnailResponse ThumbnailService Scalar Value Types ocis/services/thumbnails/v0/thumbnails.proto GetThumbnailRequest A request to retrieve a thumbnail
Field Type Label Description filepath string The path to the source image thumbnail_type ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.ThumbnailType The type to which the thumbnail should get encoded to. width int32 The width of the thumbnail height int32 The height of the thumbnail processor string Indicates which image processor to use webdav_source ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.WebdavSource cs3_source ocis.messages.thumbnails.v0.CS3Source GetThumbnailResponse The service response</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.eventhistory.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_eventhistory_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_eventhistory_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto Event Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/eventhistory/v0/eventhistory.proto Event Field Type Label Description type string REQUIRED. id string REQUIRED. event bytes REQUIRED Scalar Value Types .proto Type Notes C++ Java double double double float float float int32 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers – if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint32 instead. int32 int int64 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers – if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint64 instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.policies.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_policies_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_policies_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/policies/v0/policies.proto Environment Request Resource Resource.ID User User.ID Stage Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/policies/v0/policies.proto Environment Field Type Label Description stage Stage user User request Request resource Resource Request Field Type Label Description method string path string Resource Field Type Label Description id Resource.ID name string size uint64 url string Resource.ID Field Type Label Description storage_id string opaque_id string space_id string User Field Type Label Description id User.ID username string mail string display_name string groups string repeated User.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto Audio Entity GeoCoordinates Match Reference ResourceID Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/search/v0/search.proto Audio Field Type Label Description album string optional albumArtist string optional artist string optional bitrate int64 optional composers string optional copyright string optional disc int32 optional discCount int32 optional duration int64 optional genre string optional hasDrm bool optional isVariableBitrate bool optional title string optional track int32 optional trackCount int32 optional year int32 optional Entity Field Type Label Description ref Reference id ResourceID name string etag string size uint64 last_modified_time google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.settings.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_settings_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto Bool Bundle Identifier Int ListOption ListOptionValue ListValue MultiChoiceList Permission Resource Setting SingleChoiceList String UserRoleAssignment Value ValueWithIdentifier Bundle.Type Permission.Constraint Permission.Operation Resource.Type Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/settings/v0/settings.proto Bool Field Type Label Description default bool @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; label string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;label&amp;rdquo; Bundle Field Type Label Description id string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;id&amp;rdquo; name string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; type Bundle.Type @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo; extension string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;extension&amp;rdquo; display_name string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;display_name&amp;rdquo; settings Setting repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;settings&amp;rdquo; resource Resource @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;resource&amp;rdquo; Identifier Field Type Label Description extension string bundle string setting string Int Field Type Label Description default int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; min int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;min&amp;rdquo; max int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;max&amp;rdquo; step int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;step&amp;rdquo; placeholder string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;placeholder&amp;rdquo; ListOption Field Type Label Description value ListOptionValue @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; default bool @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; display_value string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;display_value&amp;rdquo; ListOptionValue Field Type Label Description string_value string @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;string_value&amp;rdquo; int_value int64 @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;int_value&amp;rdquo; ListValue Field Type Label Description values ListOptionValue repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;values&amp;rdquo; MultiChoiceList Field Type Label Description options ListOption repeated @gotags: yaml:&amp;ldquo;options&amp;rdquo; Permission Field Type Label Description operation Permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.messages.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_messages_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto DeleteOptions Field ListOptions ReadOptions ReadOptions.WhereEntry Record Record.MetadataEntry WriteOptions Scalar Value Types ocis/messages/store/v0/store.proto DeleteOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string Field Field Type Label Description type string type of value e.g string, int, int64, bool, float64 value string the actual value ListOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string prefix string suffix string limit uint64 offset uint64 ReadOptions Field Type Label Description database string table string prefix bool suffix bool limit uint64 offset uint64 where ReadOptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.policies.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_policies_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_policies_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/policies/v0/policies.proto EvaluateRequest EvaluateResponse policiesProvider Scalar Value Types ocis/services/policies/v0/policies.proto EvaluateRequest Field Type Label Description query string environment ocis.messages.policies.v0.Environment EvaluateResponse Field Type Label Description result bool policiesProvider Method Name Request Type Response Type Description Evaluate EvaluateRequest EvaluateResponse Scalar Value Types .proto Type Notes C++ Java double double double float float float int32 Uses variable-length encoding. Inefficient for encoding negative numbers – if your field is likely to have negative values, use sint32 instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.search.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_search_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto IndexSpaceRequest IndexSpaceResponse SearchIndexRequest SearchIndexResponse SearchRequest SearchResponse IndexProvider SearchProvider Scalar Value Types ocis/services/search/v0/search.proto IndexSpaceRequest Field Type Label Description space_id string user_id string IndexSpaceResponse SearchIndexRequest Field Type Label Description page_size int32 Optional. The maximum number of entries to return in the response page_token string Optional. A pagination token returned from a previous call to Get
that indicates from where search should continue query string ref ocis.messages.search.v0.Reference SearchIndexResponse Field Type Label Description matches ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ocis.services.store.v0</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/apis/grpc_apis/ocis_services_store_v0/</guid>
      <description>ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto DatabasesRequest DatabasesResponse DeleteRequest DeleteResponse ListRequest ListResponse ReadRequest ReadResponse TablesRequest TablesResponse WriteRequest WriteResponse Store Scalar Value Types ocis/services/store/v0/store.proto DatabasesRequest DatabasesResponse Field Type Label Description databases string repeated DeleteRequest Field Type Label Description key string options ocis.messages.store.v0.DeleteOptions DeleteResponse ListRequest Field Type Label Description options ocis.messages.store.v0.ListOptions ListResponse Field Type Label Description keys string repeated ReadRequest Field Type Label Description key string options ocis.messages.store.v0.ReadOptions ReadResponse Field Type Label Description records ocis.messages.store.v0.Record repeated TablesRequest Field Type Label Description database string TablesResponse Field Type Label Description tables string repeated WriteRequest Field Type Label Description record ocis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
