<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oCIS CLI Commands on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oCIS CLI Commands on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create a New CLI Command</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/create-new-cli-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/create-new-cli-command/</guid>
      <description>CLI Embedded in a Service CLI Independent of a Service Existing commands should be checked for commonly used options whenever a new CLI command is created, regardless of whether it is embedded in a service or not. For an example you can see the Service Independent CLI documentation. CLI Embedded in a Service These commands are usually located in the &amp;lt;service-name&amp;gt;/pkg/command subfolder.&#xA;CLI Independent of a Service These commands are located in the ocis/pkg/command subfolder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document CLI Commands</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/document-cli-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/document-cli-commands/</guid>
      <description>Type of CLI Commands Rules Any CLI command that is added to Infinite Scale must be documented here in the dev docs and the admin docs. Note that the admin docs primarily distinguish between online and offline commands because the structure of the documentation is different. Typically, any command documented in the developer documentation is integrated into the admin documentation and adapted according to the target audience. The description here is for developers; the admin docs are derived from it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Dependent CLI</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/service_dependent_cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/service_dependent_cli/</guid>
      <description>This document describes ocis CLI commands that are embedded in a service.&#xA;Common Parameters List of CLI Commands Common Parameters The ocis package offers a variety of CLI commands for monitoring or repairing ocis installations. Most of these commands have common parameters such as:&#xA;--help (or -h)&#xA;Use to print all available options.&#xA;--basePath (or -p)&#xA;Needs to point to a storage provider, paths can vary depending on your ocis installation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Independent CLI</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/service_independent_cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/cli-commands/service_independent_cli/</guid>
      <description>This document describes ocis CLI commands that are service independent.&#xA;Common Parameters List of CLI Commands Backup CLI Cleanup Orphaned Grants Cleanup Orphaned Shares List Unified Roles Move Stuck Uploads Revisions CLI Service Health Trash CLI For service dependent CLI commands, see the following services:&#xA;Auth-App Graph Postprocessing Storage-Users Common Parameters The ocis package offers a variety of CLI commands for monitoring or repairing ocis installations. Most of these commands have common parameters such as:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
