<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Settings on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Settings on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Configuration  Configuration using config files Environment variables Commandline flags settings health settings ocis-settings settings server settings version       Configuration Configuration using config files Out of the box extensions will attempt to read configuration details from:
/etc/ocis $HOME/.ocis ./config For this configuration to be picked up, have a look at your extension root command and look for which default config name it has assigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Bundles</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/bundles/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Bundle is a collection of settings, uniquely identified by the key of the extension registering the bundle and the key of the bundle itself. It&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to let oCIS extensions define settings and make them available to users. They are dynamically rendered into forms, available in the frontend.
As of now we support five different types of settings:
 boolean integer string single choice list of integers or strings multiple choice list of integers or strings  Each Setting is uniquely identified by a key within the bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRPC API</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/grpc/</guid>
      <description>settings.proto  AddSettingToBundleRequest AddSettingToBundleResponse AssignRoleToUserRequest AssignRoleToUserResponse Bool Bundle GetBundleRequest GetBundleResponse GetPermissionByIDRequest GetPermissionByIDResponse GetValueByUniqueIdentifiersRequest GetValueRequest GetValueResponse Identifier Int ListBundlesRequest ListBundlesResponse ListOption ListOptionValue ListPermissionsByResourceRequest ListPermissionsByResourceResponse ListRoleAssignmentsRequest ListRoleAssignmentsResponse ListValue ListValuesRequest ListValuesResponse MultiChoiceList Permission RemoveRoleFromUserRequest RemoveSettingFromBundleRequest Resource SaveBundleRequest   requests and responses for settings bundles  SaveBundleResponse SaveValueRequest SaveValueResponse Setting SingleChoiceList String UserRoleAssignment Value ValueWithIdentifier Bundle.Type Permission.Constraint Permission.Operation Resource.Type BundleService PermissionService RoleService ValueService   Scalar Value Types     settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Values</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/values/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Value is the value an authenticated user has chosen for a specific setting, defined in a settings bundle. For choosing settings values as a user the sole entry point is the ocis-web extension provided by this service.
Identifying settings values A settings value is uniquely identified by four attributes. Three of them are coming from the definition of the setting within it&amp;rsquo;s settings bundle (see Settings Bundles for an example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/extensions/settings/glossary/</guid>
      <description>In the context of this extension and oCIS in general, we are using the following terminology.
Configuration  System configuration e.g. service host names and ports Changes need to be propagated to other services Typically modified on the CLI  Settings  Application level settings e.g. default language Can be modified at runtime without restarting the service Typically modified in the UI  Preferences  User settings Subset of &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>