<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Settings on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Settings on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Installation  Docker Binaries   Configuration  Envrionment variables  Global Server Health   Commandline flags  Global Server Health   Configuration file   Usage  Server Health   Metrics     Installation So far we are offering two different variants for the installation. You can choose between Docker or pre-built binaries which are stored on our download mirrors and GitHub releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/building/</guid>
      <description>Backend     As this project is built with Go, so you need to install that first. The installation of Go is out of the scope of this document, please follow the official documentation for Go, to build this project you have to install Go &amp;gt;= v1.12. After the installation of the required tools you need to get the sources:
git clone https://github.com/owncloud/ocis-settings.git cd ocis-settings All required tool besides Go itself and make are bundled or getting automatically installed within the GOPATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Bundles</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/bundles/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Bundle is a collection of settings, uniquely identified by the key of the extension registering the bundle and the key of the bundle itself. It&amp;rsquo;s purpose is to let oCIS extensions define settings and make them available to users. They are dynamically rendered into forms, available in the frontend.
As of now we support five different types of settings:
 boolean integer string single choice list of integers or strings multiple choice list of integers or strings  Each Setting is uniquely identified by a key within the bundle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings Values</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/values/</guid>
      <description>A Settings Value is the value an authenticated user has chosen for a specific setting, defined in a settings bundle. For choosing settings values as a user the sole entry point is the ocis-web extension provided by this service.
Identifying settings values A settings value is uniquely identified by four attributes. Three of them are coming from the definition of the setting within it&amp;rsquo;s settings bundle (see Settings Bundles for an example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/glossary/</guid>
      <description>In the context of this extension and oCIS in general, we are using the following terminology.
Configuration  System configuration e.g. service host names and ports Changes need to be propagated to other services Typically modified on the CLI  Settings  Application level settings e.g. default language Can be modified at runtime without restarting the service Typically modified in the UI  Preferences  User settings Subset of &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.github.io/extensions/settings/license/</guid>
      <description>This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license. For the license of the used libraries you have to check the respective sources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>