<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storage backends on ownCloud</title>
    <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage backends on ownCloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cephfs</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/cephfs/</guid>
      <description>Development Architecture Implemented Aspects Future work      oCIS intends to make the aspects of existing storage systems available as transparently as possible, but the static sync algorithm of the desktop client relies on some form of recursive change time propagation on the server side to detect changes. While this can be bolted on top of existing file systems with inotify, the kernel audit or a fuse based overlay filesystem, a storage system that already implements this aspect is preferable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decomposed FS on NFS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/dcfsnfs/</guid>
      <description>NFS Server Setup NFS Client Mount oCIS Start using the NFS Share      oCIS&amp;rsquo; default storage backend is the Decomposed FS. The Decomposed FS can be set up to run on a NFS share. That way the same storage can be provided over the network to other nodes running oCIS.
This document summarizes a few important considerations of the NFS setup and describes a tested setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOS</title>
      <link>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://owncloud.dev/ocis/storage-backends/eos/</guid>
      <description>Docker dev environment for eos storage  1. Start eos &amp;amp; ocis containers 2. LDAP support 3. Home storage 4. Users storage 5. Metadata storage 6. Accounts service   Verification Further exploration Cleaning up Troubleshooting  Docker-compose exits right away Where are the logs ? How do I update a service in the ocis container? Creation and upload of files does not work Uploading big files appears to hang Running out of space quickly        oCIS can be configured to run on top of eos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
